<deck name="Rider Waite">
	<author>Brigit Esselmont</author>
	<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings</source>
	<suit name="Wands" affinity="Fire">
		<card name="Ace">
			<number>1</number>
			<file>22.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Ace of Wands is a sign to just 'go for it'. This highly action-oriented
card sees you feeling incredibly inspired and enthusiastic about pursuing a
new idea or project that you have in mind. You are all revved up and raring to
go. Use your creative energy and passion to take the first steps and get this
project underway. Even if you like to have everything planned out before you
begin down a certain path, the Ace of Wands is encouraging you to listen to
your instincts and follow your gut. If it feels like a good idea, it probably
is. So, start with a few basic actions to get things underway, and then
continue to grow and develop your ideas through more complex actions later on.
The important thing is that you act now, rather than spending more time
planning or researching.  
  
The Ace of Wands is also indicative of a time in your life where you have a
'breakthrough moment' and feel very inspired and motivated about a particular
idea or passion. Your eyes have been opened to a whole new world and you are
now very excited about the possibilities and the opportunities that are
available to you.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Ace of Wands suggests that you are finding it difficult to
clearly define what it is that you want. This lack of direction may be sapping
your energy levels and leaving you feeling incredibly unmotivated and
uninspired. As a result, you are often asking yourself if this is what you
really want in life and whether there would be something better elsewhere.
However, when you think about what other opportunities might appeal, you may
struggle to really know what you want. To remedy this, you need to first focus
on where your true passions lie. There is no point working towards a goal if
you are not motivated or excited about reaching that goal. So, take some time
to contemplate what it is you really aspire to and what you want to achieve
out of this situation.  
  
The Ace of Wands reversed can also indicate that you are weighed down by
existing responsibilities and commitments and therefore cannot pursue the new
ideas that you have. You need to revisit the Ten of Wands and release yourself
of some of those burdensome responsibilities so that you can free up your time
to pursue your newfound passions. Alternatively, you may take a break from
your usual routine in order to allow your new ideas to flourish and grow.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/ace-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Two">
			<number>2</number>
			<file>23.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Two of Wands takes the spark of inspiration from the Ace of Wands and
matures it into an actual path forward. Thus, the Two of Wands is all about
planning and progressing. You have been able to take your idea and turn it
into a feasible plan that you know will lead to your success. It is no longer
just an idea but you now have a plan in place to ensure that your idea is
carried out as you had intended.  
  
The Two of Wands is also about discovery, particularly as you step outside of
your comfort zone and explore new worlds and new experiences. It may take some
courage to take the first step but this card gives you the confidence of self-
knowledge. You know what your goal is, what your creative process is directing
for you, and you are confident in its eventual fulfilment.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Two of Wands reversed suggests that you need to start organising your
long-term goals and prioritising what is important to you and what you really
want to achieve. At the moment, it may seem that you want so many things but
you have not thought these through enough to make them a reality. Start at the
beginning again and meditate on what is important to you and what motivates
and drives you. Look at where your passions are, and then start planning how
you will achieve these goals.  
  
You may also be afraid to step out into unknown territories, despite the huge
growth potential, instead preferring to stay with what is familiar to you. The
trouble is your growth is current being stunted in your present environment
and your world has become too small for you. It is time to bring your
attention back to your original goal and understand the beneficial impact of
taking a risk and stepping out into the bigger world around you.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/two-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Three">
			<number>3</number>
			<file>24.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Three of Wands indicates opportunities to expand your horizons, through
study, travel, business enterprise and learning. You need to become more aware
of the opportunities that exist for you right now as there may be more than
you are aware of. To best see and take advantage of them you must concentrate,
cooperate and remain open-minded. You may be more aware that your best
opportunities lie outside of your current environment, so it is time to think
BIG. Consider what you can do to open doors for yourself and create more
development and self-exploration opportunities. It also signifies the changes
and challenges that are up ahead and that are associated with expanding your
horizons and entering new territories. Given the man in this card can see far
ahead of himself, then you are likely to already be aware of the upcoming
changes and challenges and can prepare for them ahead of time.  
  
Similarly, this card is also about embracing change and adopting a longer-term
view. It indicates you are in a position of strength as you control what
happens around you. Thus, this is a card of vision and foresight and looking
for greater possibilities. You are being encouraged to become a visionary and
to dream beyond your current limitations. Now is the time to accept your
vision and be confident that you will achieve it. Move fearlessly into new
areas.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Three of Wands reversed suggests that you have attempted to embark on your
own journey of personal development but you have been unable to accomplish the
goals that you had hoped for. There may have been some unexpected delays and
creative blockages to your path. There is disappointment and frustration, and
a general feeling that you may have just wasted your time by even starting on
this journey. What you may not realise, however, is that these setbacks are in
fact an important part of your bigger life journey and will have contributed
to your personal development anyway.  
  
You may also be struggling to put your plans into action and you are now
feeling worried that you have gotten in over your head and tasks appear
overwhelming. You may have had a lack of foresight and were unable to detect
the challenges as they arose, or you may have been unrealistic about the risks
associated with your plans. Break down your plans into smaller tasks to make
them more manageable and more realistic. Conduct a risk assessment ahead of
time to understand what challenges you may potentially face, and then create
mitigation plans to avoid or minimise those risks.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/three-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Four">
			<number>4</number>
			<file>25.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Four of Wands heralds celebration, good times, a happy and harmonious home
environment and good news. In numerology, four symbolises stability and firm
foundations, and in the case of the Four of Wands, you are now enjoying a
period of happiness and stability. This card indicates a sense of harmony and
balance as well as completion, and thus symbolises a time of peace and joy in
life that come as the result of often difficult and challenging effort. The
Four of Wands is one of the most positive cards in the Tarot deck and
indicates general good fortune, satisfaction, and fulfilment.  
  
With the Four of Wands, it is the perfect time to get together with your
family and friends and to celebrate all the wonderful times that you have had
together. Often, this card reflects the holiday period where you get together
with the extended family and join in a celebration. Alternatively, it may be
as simple as inviting your closest friends over for an intimate dinner and a
few glasses of nice wine. The Four of Wands often points to a marriage,
engagement, birth of a child, a birthday, graduation or other type of
celebration that marks a special milestone.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Four of Wands reversed suggests there is a lack of harmony or a breakdown
in communication in your family or home. There may be tension between family
members or loved ones and you are finding yourself getting caught up in other
people's concerns and relationship problems. This may leave you feeling
uncertain about your own relationships and what you can and cannot depend on.
You may also be going through a period of transition in your family and home
life and feeling some tension as a result.  
  
Similarly, you may find your home situation becomes increasingly unstable.
There may be an external threat to the peace and happiness you once had in
your home. You may be placed into a temporary situation which appeases your
immediate concerns but does not yet solve the longer-term issues. Depending on
your living arrangements, it may be better to move home for the time being to
allow things to settle.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/four-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Five">
			<number>5</number>
			<file>26.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>In the Tarot, the Fives typically represent conflict and change, and this is
no different for the Five of Wands. This card indicates that you are in the
midst of conflict, tension and competition and it is impacting your ability to
move forward with your goals. Rather than being able to work together with
others, you are coming up against it and are constantly being challenged on
your point of view. The trouble is that everyone is trying to express their
point of view and opinions but no-one is listening, and so there is little
progress. There is only conflict, and there is little or no value in the
discussions that are occurring. Similarly, this card is representative of a
group of people who are committed to an end but they cannot fully agree on how
to implement this goal, as each has their individual agenda as to how to bring
this to fruition. Aim to turn this into constructive conflict by allowing each
person to openly share their thoughts but then listen to other people's
thoughts. Once everyone has been heard and all opinions have been considered,
determine the best path forward.  
  
Sometimes, this type of conflict and discussion can be very positive, such as
in the case of group brainstorming and problem-solving. You need a positive
environment where you can test your ideas and have them challenged, and
improved, by others. You may benefit by establishing a working group,
committee, or 'mastermind' group with other individuals who bring varying
perspectives and experiences. Be open to this type of conflict and discussion
as a positive contribution to improving the quality of your ideas and actions.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Five of Wands reversed can suggest that you have tendency to avoid
conflict wherever possible. You may find that any sort of tension or conflict
makes you feel quite uneasy and you wish it would just go away. So, you
deflect a lot of that energy and just ignore the problem, if there is one. The
trouble, however, is that in doing this, you may just be pushing some of your
own concerns to the side, without really dealing with them or being assertive
about them. Some conflict can be good, particularly if it is constructive and
teases out the underlying issues in a way that then generates a better
solution. Consider whether always avoiding conflict is the best way to go, or
if you are finding yourself just compromising on what is important to you.  
  
The Five of Wands reversed is like a sigh of relief after conflict and
struggle. You are no longer up against so much competition and can just 'be'.
On more personal level, you have worked through your anger and hostility and
you feel more secure in your relationships. You do not have to constantly
prove yourself anymore.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/five-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Six">
			<number>6</number>
			<file>27.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Six of Wands focused on creating success and building your personal brand
and reputation. You want to be successful at what you do but at the same time,
you want to ensure that others know about it and give you the recognition you
deserve. You may need to promote yourself more frequently by sharing your
success stories with others and encouraging them to follow a similar journey.
If you do not already, you will soon have some great success stories to share
within your personal networks. You may even be interested in applying for
awards or scholarships in order to build your brand and receive public
recognition.  
  
The downside to the Six of Wands is that it can also bring self-importance,
arrogance and egotistical behaviours. With victory you may come to think that
nobody can be better than you and you end up with an inflated ego and a big
head. If you take on this attitude, someone is likely to want to take you down
and criticise you, bringing disappointment and potential disrepute later on.
If empowered by the energy of the Six of Wands, keep in mind how you would
feel if someone made you feel inferior or put you down. Reign in your ego and
make your victory all the sweeter.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Six of Wands may suggest that you have had a fall from grace and
have not received the public recognition you were seeking. You have either
received no feedback for your efforts, or negative feedback. You may have
expected things would have worked well but instead you are being punished in
some way or you are being neglected for your efforts thus far. Now, your
confidence has taken a hit, as has your professional reputation or at least
your perception of your reputation. If a particular project has not been as
successful as you had hoped, you may be better off moving to a new environment
so that you can rebuild your personal reputation and brand, rather than trying
to fix something that has already broken.  
  
The Six of Wands reversed suggests that you may be trying to achieve too many
things at once and may not be doing a good job at juggling all of these
commitments. It may be best to focus on only a few things and do them well.
This will help you feel more inspired and motivated about the activities you
do commit to.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/six-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Seven">
			<number>7</number>
			<file>28.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>Similar to the Five of Wands, the Seven of Wands indicates a struggle after
initial satisfaction and fulfilment. This time, however, the struggle is about
maintaining your position at the top while others compete and fight to achieve
the same success and status that you have already achieved. Thus, competition
is rife and you must continually prove yourself with the Seven of Wands. If
your vision and creative effort is fulfilled to the point where there is
public acclaim or acceptance of your success then you must expect competition
and challenge, as other people will no doubt also desire the same things as
you.  
  
The Seven of Wands can also indicate a challenge to the continued success of a
venture or creative project from an external source. While it appears to block
your path forward, you can overcome this challenge or obstacle by drawing upon
your strong self-confidence, self-belief and continual self-improvement. It
can also be overcome with effort and clarity of purpose.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Seven of Wands reflects that you are feeling overwhelmed by the
challenges and responsibilities in your life, finding yourself quickly snowed
under and unable to look at the bigger picture. You may have taken on too many
commitments and are now looking for an opportunity to focus your attention on
only one or two things and do those things well. You may also feel as though
you are having to compete against or are constantly comparing yourself to
others, leaving you feeling somewhat inadequate and vulnerable. There is a
need to return to the Six of Wands, which is all about building your own self-
esteem and confidence, and having faith that you can achieve what you set out
to.  
  
The Seven of Wands reversed can also indicate that you feel as though you are
constantly being judged or criticised by others. Your family or friends are
questioning you on why you are doing certain things, such as staying in a
challenging relationship or an unfulfilling job. You would prefer if they
could just keep their mouths shut and let you be!

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/seven-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Eight">
			<number>8</number>
			<file>29.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Eight of Wands represents a very focused kind of motion and activity. The
Eights are all about structure while the Wands are about raw energy. Thus, the
structure of the Eight creates a channel through which the raw energy can
flow. You are so sure about your goal that all distractions have been removed
and you can devote yourself to the task with complete concentration,
determination, and will. This experience can be very productive, allowing you
to accomplish a lot in short time.  
  
With the Eight of Wands, you can look forward to the rapid completion of a
project that is currently underway but you can also expect to be occupied by
something new and even more exciting and inspiring very soon. There really is
no stopping you right now as you are just bursting with energy and ideas, and
cannot wait to achieve one task in order to start another. To maximise this
energy, it is important to ensure that your activities are focused on your
broader goals and that you are investing in the right things at the right
time. Also, make sure that before you move to the next task, your previous
task is complete.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Eight of Wands reversed can indicate significant delays, particularly with
regard to travel or fast-moving plans. Despite having a lot of energy and
enthusiasm to progress things forward, you are now being faced with multiple
obstacles in your course. This is incredibly frustrating and you may be
growing increasingly impatient by the day. Keep looking for alternative ways
around the obstacles presented so that you can carry out your plans.  
  
On the flipside, the reversed Eight of Wands suggests that you are charging
ahead with an idea or plan but you need to slow down and consider your next
steps before continuing. You may be missing something in your haste and prone
to making mistakes. Similarly, this card can be a sign to hold off your
activities for a short amount of time until the situation becomes more stable
and predictable.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/eight-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Nine">
			<number>9</number>
			<file>30.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Nine of Wands suggests that you are so close to completing a particular
project or task but at the last minute, you are faced with yet another
challenge or setback. Know that you have the inner resources necessary to
overcome any difficulty you encounter, even though it may seem impossible at
the time. You are so close to finally achieving success, do not give up now!
The Nine of Wands is a sign of hope and encouragement that if you stand firm
and strong against your challenges, you will achieve your goal. The challenges
before you now are only the last bit of darkness before the break of a
wonderful dawn.  
  
Sometimes, the Nine of Wands encourages a risk-averse approach. You need to
expect the worst and therefore take extra precautions to avoid any negative
consequences to your plans. You need to be on guard and wary of any potential
obstacles or opponents who may stand in your way.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Nine of Wands reversed suggests that you may be hesitant to make a long-
term commitment. You may be feeling as if life is all work and no play, and
you may feel overcome by responsibilities or a lack of support from those
around you. You may also be lacking the necessary resources, such as finances,
skills or time, in order to deal with the challenges head on. As such, you are
hesitant to make any commitments in fear that your responsibilities will
become all too much.  
  
You may also be more inclined to be a little 'on edge' and on the defensive.
The boundaries you have set around yourself are now becoming your cage,
locking you into your old habits and behaviours. Be careful of dwelling on
past frustrations and grievances. Just try to let go.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/nine-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Ten">
			<number>10</number>
			<file>31.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Tens in Tarot represent the completion of a cycle, and thus with the Ten
of Wands, you have reached the end of a cycle after a period of struggle. You
are finally reaping your rewards after investing a lot of hard work and
effort. You have fulfilled a creative venture, realised a dream or
accomplished a major goal, and now must deal with the consequences of that
fulfilment.  
  
However, the Ten of Wands suggests that even with the achievement of your
goal, there comes with it great responsibilities and commitments. While you
have reached a point of completion, you are becoming starkly aware that you
must now carry on with the responsibilities you have laid out for yourself, in
order to ensure ongoing success. The trouble is, however, that these
responsibilities may become too much to bear and you are struggling to let go.
It is a bit like the business owner who creates a flourishing business but who
is unprepared to delegate some of his/her responsibilities to the staff, and
ends up working 70-80 hours a week. The inspiration and creativity that was
associated with the initial goal or vision rapidly disappears, and everything
becomes hard work all too quickly. Thus, it is incredibly important to let go
of or delegate some of your responsibilities in order to free you up to still
enjoy life.

</normal>
				<reversed>Upright, the Ten of Wands reflects that you have taken on a heavy burden.
Reversed, the Ten of Wands indicates that you are unnecessarily holding on to
this burden when you do not need to. If you are feeling weighed down by your
present circumstances, look at different ways you can lighten the load. Can
you delegate certain tasks and responsibilities? Are you worrying about
matters that do not concern you or cannot be changed? Do not become a martyr
and take on more than you can realistically handle.  
  
Sometimes, the reversed Ten of Wands indicates that you are avoiding
responsibility and making it even more difficult for others who must take on
your share. Thus, the saying, "You have made your bed, now lie in it," is very
appropriate for this card.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/ten-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Page">
			<number/>
			<file>32.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Page of Wands is similar to the Fool in that he is a free spirit who
represents change and new beginnings. He has a true passion for life, despite
his understanding of this world is not yet fully developed. He has not yet
been weighed down by the burdens of the material world, coming and going as he
pleases, and usually encouraging change wherever he goes. He is like the
catalyst that inspires changes that might be impossible in any other
situation.  
  
The appearance of the Page of Wands indicates that you are experiencing a
creative restlessness within you that is just waiting for some sort of
expression, or, you may be on the verge of some sort of discovery or new phase
of life. The Page of Wands represents the sudden creative spark that comes to
you, suddenly and unexpectedly, and that starts you down the road of a new
creative vision. Thus, he encourages you to express yourself and your
individuality with light-hearted abandon. Listen to your unconscious mind and
follow your creative urges, even if you are worried about being the lonely
voice crying out in the wilderness. With persistence and a balanced
perspective even the immature desires of the Page of Wands can be transformed
into a beautiful creative vision that can change the world.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Page of Wands reversed suggests that you have tried a few new ventures or
projects but these have not been particularly successful. You may have had a
vision to start a new hobby or project, with the view that it would lead to
bigger and better things but you soon realised that you had taken the wrong
approach and it wasn't leading to the growth and development you had expected.
You may have started to realise that you had not really focused enough on what
your goals and objectives were and that is why you were not reaching the
outcomes you wanted. Luckily, you had not progressed too far along and were
able to easily retreat from those projects with limited impact. Sometimes,
too, these setbacks can be helpful in testing out new territories and
exploring what will and will not work for you.  
  
You may also find that your eagerness to start something new has been
negatively impacted by complexities, obstacles and opposition, which has
resulted in a lack of motivation and indecisiveness about your path forward.
You may also be fearful of whether you can really get your project or idea up
and running, or if you are just going to be weighed down by more
responsibility and troubles.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/page-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Knight">
			<number/>
			<file>33.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>Whereas the Page of Wands indicated the initial spark of a new idea, the
Knight of Wands indicates the actual pursuit of that idea. There is
significantly more action associated with this Knight and he has a true
commitment and energy to make sure his ideas are put into action. His courage
is incredibly strong and he has no fear of anything. He simply charges forth
with his ideas and visions to make things happen. Thus, the Knight of Wands
suggests that your confidence levels will rapidly increase and you will feel
ready to take on the world with your vision. Tackle any challenges that stand
in your way and always be ready to help others who lack your determination and
exuberance but who desperately need it.  
  
The Knight of Wands is an 'act first, think later' type of guy. He is
impatient and impulsive, with a love for action. The downside to the Knight of
Wands is that while he is bursting with energy and enthusiasm, he has a
tendency to rush into things without much consideration for the consequences
of his actions. He sets off on his journey in haste and often fails to have a
clear plan of attack and this may negatively impact his chances of longer-term
success. He is so focused on being the best and of fame and glory that he
almost forgets to plan ahead and to keep sight of reality. The Knight of Wands
can also come across as aggressive and overly ambitious. He is highly
insistent even if others stand in his way, criticise him or challenge him.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Knight of Wands reversed indicates delays and frustration, getting
nowhere, and feeling anger at obstacles and at being denied what you want to
have. This card, in the reversed position, represents a loss of personal power
or the negative use of power. It can indicate that you are trying to
camouflage or compensate for your inability to control this situation.
Accompanying emotions may involve a loss of self-esteem and pessimism.  
  
This Knight, when reversed, is impulsive, restless, impatient and lacking in
foresight. He is so keen to just pursue his own interests or hurry things
along that he fails to really understand whether he will be successful or what
the consequences of his actions will be. If this is you, you need to be very
careful of not rushing into things without thinking it through first. Even if
you are starting to get frustrated with a lack of action, you need to consider
the consequences before doing something. If this is someone in your life, then
it is best to steer clear of them for the time being. They need to make these
mistakes in their life to learn and improve, and cannot necessarily be
controlled or held back at this point.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/knight-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Queen">
			<number/>
			<file>34.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Queen of Wands is the dominant feminine energy of the element of Fire. She
is not afraid to demonstrate her power to others nor does she shy away from a
challenge. She is therefore a strong leader who is focused on her desires,
intending to get what she wants. Thus, the Queen of Wands indicates that you
are strong, independent and able to take care of yourself and sustain your own
creative vision, even in the face of adversity. You know what you want and how
to get it, and you are masterful at engaging with others to achieve your
goals. You are talented at staying fiercely determined and focused on your own
goals whilst being friendly and optimistic with those around you.  
  
The Queen of Wands is highly energetic and leads a busy and active life. She
radiates health and vitality and has an inner vibrancy that fills her with
ongoing energy and inspiration. This Queen is a natural-born, intelligent
leader who actively inspires others. She can be quite the 'mover and shaker',
influencing others through her vision, courage and determination. She instils
confidence within you and gives you the power and self-assurance that you can
achieve anything that you set your mind to.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Queen of Wands reversed card describes a situation in which someone is
behaving in a manipulative, pushy or selfish way. One of you seems to be in a
chronically bad mood, and is angry, resentful and jealous. You may find
yourself being attacked or bullied, or behaving this way yourself. Perceptions
are skewed and information is being twisted into lies. Someone is demanding,
controlling, petty and narrow-minded.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/queen-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="King">
			<number/>
			<file>35.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The King of Wands represents pure fire energy. Unlike the other Wands court
cards, he is not so interesting in actual creation and creativity, or in
dreaming up ideas and implementing them himself. Instead, he is more inclined
to take an idea and change the world to match his vision. As such he is a
natural-born leader of all kinds of people, and he is very visionary. Once he
sets himself a goal, he sticks to it and ensures that he can make it happen
with the support of those around him. People naturally gravitate towards this
King as they know he will get things done and will do it very well. He is a
master, too, at being able to get other people to do his work for him, and
keep them on-side throughout the process.  
  
The King of Wands looks forward to challenges because he enjoys the natural
rush of adrenaline associated with solving a difficult problem and coming to a
solution that will benefit not just one person but many people. In the
process, he not only rids himself of his own fear but that of others, by
reassuring them that they shall all succeed. He is not all talk, either, and
when the going gets tough, he is prepared to do the hard yards to see
something through to the end. The King of Wands has a deep and innate respect
for other people, and his compassion extends far. He knows how to bring out
the best in others and to empower them to deliver his visions and goals, which
he knows will be of benefit to the greater population.

</normal>
				<reversed>The King of Wands reversed personality type can make rash, hasty, and
impulsive decisions. This person can be dominating, pushy, and overbearing at
times. This is rarely done with malice or an intention to make someone else
submissive, it is just a strong tendency that sometimes takes control. The
King of Wands type usually does not even realise when he or she crosses the
line between being assertive and aggressive.  
  
At worse, the reversed King of Wands typifies the most selfish, ruthless
qualities of fire. He can denote a manipulative business contact who will use
you as long as it serves his purpose. He may be a rival, competitor or
unscrupulous opponent. In love, he represents a delightful flirtation that
could wreak emotional havoc. He is only suitable for limited liaisons, holiday
romances or brief, passionate encounters. His flames are bright and warm but
soon die down.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-wands/king-of-wands/</source>
		</card>
	</suit>
	<suit name="Cups" affinity="Water">
		<card name="Ace">
			<number>1</number>
			<file>36.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Ace of Cups represents the beginning of love, happiness and compassion. It
can indicate the start of a new relationship, be it a friendship or a romance.
This is one of those relationships where you feel butterflies in your stomach
and you are so pleased to have met someone with whom you can share a special
connection. The water in the card reflects the flow of emotion and thus the
Ace of Cups suggests that positive emotion and energy will be created between
two people in a way that leaves you feeling good about yourself and life in
general. You need to experience the feeling of new love or of giving and
receiving unconditional love. Give and accept love on a new level and open
your heart to what is around you. Your loving ways will magnetise love to you.  
  
The Ace of Cups is also about creative expression, particularly where there is
an opportunity to allow your emotions to shine through. You are very open to
experiencing your inner feelings and sharing them with others. You may be
inspired to start a new creative project, take up an art class or two, or even
engage in interpretative dance. You are at that point in your life where you
feel comfortable with who you are and what you feel and you are not afraid to
express that part of yourself to others. You see new potential in allowing
your creative juices to flow and as such, you are open to new possibilities
and stimulating your imagination to allow your talent to unfold.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Ace of Cups may call on you to curb your emotions somewhat for
your greater benefit. For example, ending a relationship may spur you on to
wanting to cry and cry for days on end but what the Ace of Cups reversed tells
us is that in order to heal, you really need to push back the tears and fight
on in order to retain a balance. Try not to let your emotions get the better
of you or take an unhealthy hold of your life. Sometimes it is possible to
express ourselves TOO much, and in doing so, share our vulnerabilities or
worse, attack the vulnerabilities of others. Find ways to constructively
express what you feel so that you can continue through life with a more
balanced perspective.  
  
Alternatively, the reversed Ace of Cups could suggest that you have repressed
your feelings too long and it is now the time to release them. You may have
bottled up so many emotions that you have become almost void of feeling true
emotions and instead feel a general 'numbness' inside. In a relationship
reading, the reversed Ace of Cups can indicate that you are withholding your
emotions, for fear of getting hurt. You know that in order for the
relationship to move forward and flow freely you must eventually trust in your
partner but for the time being, you are holding back.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/ace-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Two">
			<number>2</number>
			<file>37.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Two of Cups typically points towards a relationship that is based on
mutual attraction and romantic inclinations. It reflects the clear, nurturing,
supportive and heartfelt exchange of emotions that is the gift of a romantic
relationship. The Two of Cups represents love that is nurturing, creative,
clearly focused, inspirational and equally fulfilling. In a reading, this is
often a beautiful start to a new romance in which you will experience
understanding, harmony and deep love between two souls. The seed has blossomed
into a tree of appreciation. Kindness and thoughtfulness will bind your two
hearts together with the feeling of being simultaneously very special to one
another.  
  
Despite the focus on the two beings shown on this card, the Two of Cups also
points to what is happening within the individual. To be truly loved, deeply
treasured and valued highly by others, you must first and foremost strive to
create those feelings for yourself. That is, when you work toward loving
yourself, you hold your inner spirit in high regard, treating it with
deference and deep respect. When you see yourself in this positive light,
other people cannot help but respond to your personal sense of value in an
equally positive manner.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Two of Cups reversed may indicate a break-up or a lack of harmony within a
relationship or partnership. You may not be seeing eye-to-eye and there is
tension in your relations with each other. Each partner is finding it quite
hard to be truly honest with each other and therefore the flow of
communication is broken. There is a lack of mutual respect and understanding.
Upright, the Two of Cups is a beautiful card to have because it shows balance
and emotional connection. But reversed, it suggests that you are not on an
even playing field and this is a fundamental issue. It is as if your partner
thinks he or she is better than you or that his or her opinion matters more
than yours.  
  
Even if a relationship is going great guns, the reversed Two of Cups may be a
sign that the relationship is more physical than heart-felt. It may be a
fleeting affair rather than something more meaningful.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/two-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Three">
			<number>3</number>
			<file>38.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>More broadly, the Three of Cups indicates the end or conclusion of any
problems you have been experiencing, particularly those that relate to your
interactions with others. A compromise will be found which will serve all the
interests of those involved and will allow for a more harmonious environment.
You can facilitate this process by bringing about positive change within
yourself and changing your attitude and the way you react or deal with what is
happening. Treat the situation with compassion and give the benefit of the
doubt where possible.  
  
The Three of Cups represents community and groups of people coming together to
focus on a common goal for the greater good of others. You may find that by
reaching out to others and banding together, you can achieve a huge amount in
terms of sharing your positive energy and passion with others, benefiting the
wider community. It is a sign that you should seek out other people to
celebrate your successes along with you.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Three of Cups can indicate that your creativity is being stifled
and instead you are being forced to conform to the group in which you are
operating. You may be part of a very tight-knit group that does things a
certain way and is not open to innovation or alternative approaches. You need
to consider whether you are willing to sacrifice your creative abilities in
favour of the group's desires.  
  
On the other hand, the Three of Cups reversed may indicate over-indulgence in
the party scene. You may be spending most nights out at bars and nightclubs,
indulging in drugs and alcohol and throwing caution to the wind. You may also
be in the 'work hard, play hard' mindset, when what you need is greater
balance in your life. Be mindful about the longer-term consequences of your
actions and ask yourself whether this is indeed a sustainable lifestyle. Take
a break from the social scene to regroup and get some much needed sleep.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/three-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Four">
			<number>4</number>
			<file>39.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Four of Cups often appears when you are bored or dissatisfied with the
status quo. You may be feeling disengaged, apathetic, or unmotivated. Life has
become stale or 'flat' and there is little that excites you anymore. To
overcome this, the Four of Cups suggests a need to re-evaluate your situation
and to look deep within your own psyche to find understanding and meaning.
Turn your attention inward to find the Truth for which you are searching.
Avoid distractions and examine your heart and mind to gain clarity.  
  
Often, the Four of Cups indicates that an offer has been presented to you but
you are holding off making any sort of decision or evaluation of that
opportunity until you have had more time for reflection and consideration.
Notice that while the man in this card has not accepted the offer being
presented to him, he has not completely rejected it either. The cup will
continue to be there and the decision to accept or reject it can be made at
any point. For now, though, it is the time for contemplation, research and
meditation. When all of the answers are in, and it feels right emotionally,
then you can take action but in the short-term, you do not need to make an
immediate choice.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Four of Cups reversed suggests that there is a good possibility that an
offer will come your way but you must work hard to go out and get it. It is
sitting right under your nose, so make sure you snap it up before you miss
out! You may also be too focused on your own issues that you completely miss
this opportunity or are unaware that it even exists. Keep your eyes and heart
open to new possibilities, and release some of the focus on yourself to allow
new opportunities to appear.  
  
On a more positive note, if you have been going through a period of
stagnation, boredom or apathy, you will begin to feel restless with this state
of being, and will want to break free from this rut. Put aside any negative
thoughts or sulky behaviour. Embrace the opportunities that are already being
offered to you. Reconnect with others and let them know how much you
appreciate them.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/four-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Five">
			<number>5</number>
			<file>40.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Five of Cups represents a lack of fulfilment or non-attainment of expected
results. You are feeling disappointed that a situation has not turned out as
you had hoped, and instead of moving on to greener pastures, you are wallowing
in self-pity and regret about what has been lost. The water spilled from the
cups shows that the cause for regret is more emotional than financial. You are
quickly becoming disillusioned with life and increasingly pessimistic about
your future.  
  
The Five of Cups suggests that you are having trouble letting go of the past
and learning from your mistakes. This card can often reflect a person who is
caught up in the past and unable to move on, missing out on new opportunities.
Bitter memories from the past continue to bother you, and often a great deal
of the blame for past actions is placed on yourself and your inadequacies. To
some it would seem that there is no way out of this situation but the Tarot
always shows problems on one hand and solutions on the other.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Five of Cups shows recovery from regret and an acceptance of the
past. Now, you are beginning to realise the full implications of the past and
you have come to appreciate the lessons learned from the experience. You may
even recognise the value of the painful experience in the broader scheme of
things in preparing you for later experiences. You are ready to pick up the
remaining two cups that are full of the water of emotional growth and go on.  
  
Sometimes, the reversed Five of Cups indicates a feeling of being trapped in
the past, holding on too tightly to the might-have-beens, and not being able
to focus on the positive. The reversal could also indicate buried feelings of
regret, that you are not allowing to surface and therefore they never get
dealt with and brought to closure. Five is also the number of change, and
indicates an emotional destabilisation that is intended to create change in
how you approach your life.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/five-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Six">
			<number>6</number>
			<file>41.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Six of Cups is a card of childhood, nostalgia, naïve happiness, and
generosity. You want to return to the happy memories of your past, whether as
a child, teenager or adult. Oftentimes, though, these memories are indeed a
thing of the past and reflect aspects of your life that have since vanished.
You may feel that the only way to connect to this happiness is to escape into
the past where you can reflect on your happy and beautiful memories, instead
of dealing with current challenges. This is fine if you are simply taking a
walk down memory lane but it is important that you live in the present and
accept your current circumstances rather than always living in the past.  
  
The Six of Cups can also point to your inner child and suggests a need to
experience child-like joy. The child you were still lives within you and must
be cared for. This is often referred to as working with your inner child.
People with persistent problems such as addiction, depression, troubled
relationships and chronic dissatisfaction can transform their lives with inner
child work and find a new joy and energy in living. The source of your
problems may be in past events that are triggered in the present. We are made
up of many parts and inside we still have the little child and adolescent we
were with all of its experiences and feelings. This can lead to the inner
child reacting strongly to certain experiences, situations and feelings in the
present, based on experiences of the past. Working with your inner child and
getting to know where these feelings come from can change that and enhance
your choices in miraculous ways. When we are being playful, spontaneous,
creative, intuitive and surrendering to the spiritual self, our genuine
authentic Self, who we know deep within us, our real Self is being welcomed
and encouraged to be present.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Six of Cups is a card of nostalgia, childlike love and generosity, and a
carefree, naive outlook on life. Reversed, it suggests that you may have had
unrealistically rosy ideas about a particular stage of life, based on your
dreams and ideals from when you were younger. For example, you may have always
pictured yourself as married with children by 25, only to realise that once
you hit 25, you had other goals in mind. Or you may be disappointed that you
have reached a particular age but have not fulfilled your childhood dreams
just yet.  
  
Sometimes, the reversed Six of Cups can indicate child abuse or sexual abuse
sustained as a young person. You may still be working through these issues and
trying to release yourself from the harmful memories. Alternatively, you may
be working with others who have repressed memories from their childhood and
who need your support.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/six-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Seven">
			<number>7</number>
			<file>42.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Seven of Cups indicates that the images in your mind must be dealt with
not only in your dreams but in the world of reality. Be careful of wishful
thinking or illusions in the choices you currently face. The character in the
Seven of Cups is a dreamer who is able to see beauty and excitement as well as
fearful trials and difficulties in the future. If you are constantly caught up
in your own dreams, fantasies, and/or fears, we will never be able to move
forward and make those dreams a reality or overcome those fears.  
  
Therefore, the Seven of Cups indicates that although dreaming is beautiful and
provides inspiration for action, you must at some point abandon your 'castles
in the sky' and begin to build those castles in your real life. A choice must
be made even though the apparent multiplicity of options seems to paralyse you
with either fear or excessive anticipation. If you are unable to make a
decision because of too many options, it is time to carefully evaluate the
pros and cons of each option and make a thoughtful choice. You also need to be
very clear about what it is you are working towards so that you can make the
best choice. Make your decision with caution as all is not what it seems to
be. Great opportunities may turn out to be major problems later on, while less
enticing options may turn out to be golden opportunities.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Seven of Cups reversed is a card of illusions, temptations, and
diversionary tactics. Your views of life at this time are a bit illusory, and
may tend toward fantasies that cannot actually be realised in the real world.
There is an unwillingness to deal with the day-to-day reality of life, and a
need to get your head out of the clouds. You may be feeling unclear about what
you are really searching for in order to become fulfilled. You may also be
hiding something from yourself that probably has to do with your subconscious
emotions. These illusions and diversions need to be stripped away and seen for
what they really are. You may find that returning to the energy of the Six of
Cups and finding yourself in more familiar territory, such as the family home
or the area in which you grew up, may have a calming effect.  
  
On a more positive note, the reversed Seven of Cups can indicate a time when
you are finally breaking through a fog of confusion and illusion to focus on
your chosen goal. With resolution and purpose, you are now setting your
intentions and finding solutions.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/seven-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Eight">
			<number>8</number>
			<file>43.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Eight of Cups indicates that it is time to ask yourself what you can do to
bring a deeper satisfaction and joy to your life beyond the obvious pursuit of
material satisfaction and/or physical enjoyment. You are seeking deeper
meaning to life and focusing in on your personal truth. You want to escape
from the 'rat race' and pursue deeper, more spiritual goals at this time. You
are willing to let go of your material possessions in favour of something more
meaningful. Thus, the Eight of Cups is often reflective of the start of a
journey of discovery, particularly on a spiritual level.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Eight of Cups suggests that you may be feeling confused about
where your best options lie. Part of you wants to explore new horizons and
possibilities but another part of your fears that in doing so, you will miss
out on what your current circumstances have to offer.  
  
The reversed Eight of Cups can reflect hopeless, aimless drifting from one
place to the next by someone who cannot stand to be confined to just one
setting or someone who never quite fits in. You may fear intimacy and have
difficulty making and keeping your commitments. When things become too
difficult, you quickly escape and leave behind your troubles, rather than
dealing with them head on.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/eight-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Nine">
			<number>9</number>
			<file>44.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>Nines represent personal integrity and completion, or the final stage of
development. This final stage may bring certain problems with it, and past
experiences and methods of coping become important here and are an intrinsic
part of the meaning attached to the nines. Thus, the Nine of Cups shows a
tendency to daydream and enjoy the pleasures of life. You are likely to spend
more time thinking about big ideas and grand schemes for an ideal lifestyle
than doing the work you need to do right now to execute those ideas. While it
is good to 'think big', you also need to balance this with action to ensure
that you can fulfil your dreams.  
  
More generally, the Nine of Cups reflects happiness in all areas such as
health, finances, work, luck, love or relationships. After the difficult
choices of the Seven and the stagnation of the Eight, the Cups suit starts to
balance out with the Nine. One of the most positive and uplifting cards of the
entire deck, the Nine of Cups shows satisfaction on all levels – emotional,
physical, and sensual. It is no wonder that many Tarot readers refer to this
card as the Wish Card as its appearance is often taken as a sign that,
whatever your heart's desire, it shall be granted in the coming days or weeks.
Know that you have paved our own way on the path to success.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Nine of Cups is a card of satisfaction and wishes. When reversed, it
suggests that you may be disappointed that your wishes are not materialising
as expected. Your expectations may be unrealistic or you may not be actively
pursuing your dreams, instead hoping that they will manifest with little input
or action from you.  
  
The reversed Nine of Cups can suggest greed and a lack of concern for other
people's needs in favour of your own. You may have an inadequate regard of how
your behaviour is impacting others, and are often found gloating or boasting
about your successes while others are suffering. Be considerate, and even if
you have something to rave about, think about the impact that may have on
others.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/nine-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Ten">
			<number>10</number>
			<file>45.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Ten of Cups embodies happiness, joy, contentment and emotional fulfilment,
particularly in the area of your relationships and family. It represents
almost an idyllic state of peace, harmony and love where all your dreams and
wishes have come true and you are delighting in your good fortune. Given it is
a Ten, this card indicates attainment of this idyllic state so stop for a
moment to appreciate everything that you have accomplished and be incredibly
grateful for the blessings that fill your life right now.  
  
With the image of a happy family and a comforting home in the background, the
Ten of Cups is indicative of a harmonious and loving family life. All family
members are getting along with each other and there is a lot of happiness and
love shared. No-one is fighting or causing any tension. Instead, it is an
environment of peace and happiness that lends itself to warm and loving
relations. The presence of the Ten of Cups may even reflect an upcoming family
holiday where you can rest and relax together, creating fun and happy family
memories. There may be a family reunion or a family celebration where members
of your extended family come together. This is a wonderful time to bond with
your family and lay the foundation for a happy and harmonious future together.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Ten of Cups reversed can also highlight when there is a misalignment of
personal values. You are not living by your personal values and you are not
being true to yourself. You are allowing others to determine what will and
will not make you happy rather than looking within for that source of
fulfilment. As a result, you are questioning whether you really believe in
what you are doing. While you are madly rushing around trying to get things
done, it is also very important that you address any lingering issues of
values alignment with what you are doing; otherwise this may become a
showstopper later down the track.  
  
The reversed Ten of Cups may also suggest that you are neglecting your family
while you pursue more material goals such as progressing your career or making
more money. Your work/life balance is out of whack and you are spending less
and less quality time with your family. You need to be clear about where your
personal values lie and what is truly achievable. If you continue to neglect
your family, you will find that relationships will suffer and you may not be
able to achieve an overall sense of contentment and happiness as planned.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/ten-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Page">
			<number/>
			<file>46.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>Your unconscious mind is also trying to speak to you, possibly through your
dreams or through synchronistic encounters with significant people. The
message to be taken is that you must be open to the unexpected, occasionally
bizarre impulses of the creative spirit and not shut out inspiration simply
because it does not fit in with a rational point of view. The Page of Cups may
also be an indication that your intuition is very sharp and you may receive
messages from your unconscious mind. You may be more inclined to act on a
hunch or have a psychic experience. This is a good time to trust your
intuition and your gut feeling.  
  
This card encourages you to take a fresh perspective on a difficult issue and
to approach that situation with benefit of the doubt, love and compassion. The
Page of Cups' appearance tells you to never stop listening to your intuition
and believing in your dreams. If you cease to dream, then your dreams shall
never come true because they do not exist anymore. In your darkest moments,
dreams can often provide a ray of hope through with the Page of Cups can
manifest. Dare to dream and all things become possible.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Page of Cups reversed represents someone who is immature or has emotional
troubles. It can depict a person who is escaping through drugs or alcohol, or
someone who is running away from reality and living in their own world. This
is a person who is emotionally insecure and unable to conduct healthy
relationships as he expects too much and gives too little. He is lacking in
self-love and self-acceptance, and may be emotionally abusive. This person has
rampant and unfocused emotions, and may therefore get his or her feelings hurt
without reason. He is suspicious, self-doubting, insincere, selfish and easily
depressed. This may be someone you know or even a reflection of your shadow
self.  
  
The reversed Page of Cups can indicate that you are following an inclination
or a hunch but with little thought about whether it is realistic or not. You
may be acting without thinking or allowing your immediate desires and emotions
to seduce you, particularly if they go against your common sense, such as
making a promise you cannot keep or a commitment that does not mean anything
to you.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/page-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Knight">
			<number/>
			<file>47.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Knight of Cups is the most feminine of the Knights; although that does not
mean that he is any less of a Knight. It simply implies that he is in touch
with his intuition and emotions, and he uses them for his own good during his
quests of romance and seduction. He is charming and attractive to others,
regardless of their sex, while still expressing the romantic, poetic view of
life in his unique way. He may be in love with love itself. This Knight also
looks to his emotions to provide a map for his life direction. He is someone
who is ruled by his heart rather than his head. When faced with a decision, he
will always go with what his heart tells him, whether it is logical or not.
Decisions will be made without much thought and instead they are made drawing
upon inner direction, with the experience of warmth, friendliness, love and
the need to share these qualities with everyone.  
  
The Knight of Cups represents the undertaking of the creative adventure hinted
at in the Page of Cups. Whereas the Page encounters the mystical fish out of
the golden cup and is thus initially inspired with creativity, the Knight has
already encountered his inspiration and is about to undertake the journey of
imagination and creativity to which the unconscious has impelled him. If you
are about to start a new creative project, direct your imagination into the
real world. True imagination feeds on 'action' thus if you do nothing with
your dreams they will remain vague and unrelated to the rest of your life. The
Knight of Cups brings a warning about getting too caught up in fantasy and the
romanticism of life. Fantasy excites but it lacks any real meaning as you deny
your basic commitment to the world and your imagination produces nothing.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Knight of Cups reversed indicates a situation which was initially
incredibly appealing, romantic and exciting but which later turns out to be
something very different, and one walks away feeling quite disappointed. It is
as though you are wearing the rose-coloured glasses, or going through the
honeymoon period, only to come out realising that the situation is quite
different to what you thought.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/knight-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Queen">
			<number/>
			<file>48.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Queen of Cups is nurturing, caring, compassionate and sensitive. She is a
good wife and a loving mother as she is emotionally secure and can connect on
an emotional level with others. She is admired for her fairness and honesty,
and is warm-hearted. Often a healer, counsellor or psychic, this is a woman
who seems to know what is wrong even before you open your mouth. She seems to
have exactly the right solution to problems relating to relationships,
emotions and feelings. She easily tunes in to what you are feeling and is able
to help you make sense of it in a sensitive and compassionate manner. As such,
her intuition is very strong and she has a unique talent at being able to pick
up on emotional energy.  
  
One of the greatest assets of the Queen of Cups is her ability to sense the
needs of those around her. Due to her associations with the element of water,
the Queen of Cups can be passive and receptive. Her sensitivity draws those
who struggle and suffer towards her. In many ways, she is a safe harbor for
others. Her ability to connect on a soul level enables her to remedy the
broken hearts of others. Her warmth and genuine caring make her a beacon of
light. Because she is so responsive to the feelings of others, the Queen of
Cups must constantly uphold her boundaries between herself and others. If not
properly protected, the Queen of Cups can lose her own sense of self. This is
her greatest vulnerability.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Queen of Cups may also suggest that you are allowing your
imagination to run away with you. You mean well but unfortunately you cannot
be relied on. You are letting your emotions take hold and you are not thinking
clearly with your head. At its worst, the precious qualities of imagination
and flowing fantasy might turn out to be weakness and thoughtlessness, turning
in any direction that any wind may blow, getting lost in a dream world of
unreal fantasies. You are becoming easily overwhelmed by emotion, and you are
becoming moody, unstable, brooding, suspicious, and overly secretive.  
  
The Queen of Cups reversed represents an overemotional wreck who can be driven
to manipulative and vindictive behaviour. Your mood swings are making life
difficult for others and you are emotionally draining on those around you. You
tend to play the emotional heartstrings to your advantage. Within you, you may
also harbor angst and self-loathing for your inability to do more with
yourself and your talents.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/queen-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="King">
			<number/>
			<file>49.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The King of Cups, like all the court cards in the suit of Cups, represents
emotion, creativity, and the unconscious. Unlike the preceding three court
cards, however, the King of Cups expresses much more restraint in his
emotional state. He is a master of his own feelings, and remains in control of
his emotions. Not to say that he represses those feelings and sentiments. On
the contrary, the King of Cups represents the balance between the emotions and
the intellect. He is a master of compassion and kindness and his card often
indicates strong bonds in a relationship based on temperance and
understanding.  
  
Sometimes, the King of Cups can represent an older male who may appear in your
life. This card represents a man of business, law or divinity, who is kind,
considerate and willing to take responsibility for his actions. He is
paternalistic but in a sensitive, generous manner, and he enjoys the quiet
power associated with providing loving energy to others. He is able to listen
mindfully to others and he responds calmly in a crisis. He uses diplomacy
rather than force, and reached out to help, not to stifle or have it only his
way!

</normal>
				<reversed>The King of Cups reversed is incredibly emotionally controlling and
manipulative. This is someone who is toxic, moody, sulky and withdrawn from
others, particularly if things do not go his way. He can be vindictive and
vengeful and has a talent at being able to punish others through emotional
manipulation. He uses emotional blackmail to get his way and to push his own
agenda. He leaves you feeling uncertain about yourself and as if you are the
problem, not him. This only leads to emotional instability within you, which
is entirely undeserved. If this sounds like someone you have met in the past,
there is still some work to be done in releasing yourself from his controlling
forces.  
  
A reversed King of Cups can also represent a mature and loving, emotional
person, who has let their emotions begin controlling their life. The King of
Cups may depend too much on others and view himself through the eyes of
others. He may fall into delusions or alcoholism, or others forms of escapism
to deal with emotional pain. This could show you trapped in a relationship
with someone that is dependent and emotional, or a co-dependency situation.
You may be struggling with self-deception and/or the deceptions of others, and
the most important thing in this situation is to see yourself and others as
they actually are, with clear and loving eyes but not foster any sense of
dependence or weakness through your own actions.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-cups/king-of-cups/</source>
		</card>
	</suit>
	<suit name="Swords" affinity="Air">
		<card name="Ace">
			<number>1</number>
			<file>50.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Ace of Swords shows the beginning of a situation whose potential is as
double-edged as the blade of the sword itself. The Ace implies the use of
great power, even excessive power at times, to further one's ends but what is
not clear is how those powers will be used, or what it is that you are trying
to achieve. No matter what the goal, there is always great power behind the
attempts to reach it and, as such, very little can stand in the way of the
energy of the Ace of Swords without being destroyed.  
  
The Ace of Swords also encourages you to seek out the truth of the matter and
to find justice. You may be championing a cause or standing up for your rights
or the rights of others. Thus sometimes, the Ace of Swords can suggest that
you are prepared for 'battle'. You have great clarity on a situation and can
now argue your case with the view to come out victorious. You may have a new
idea for which you are ready to fight, or you may be all fired up on an issue
that you are particularly passionate about, such as human rights, the
environment or your personal beliefs. This card invites you to use mental
force and to use your intellect and critical reasoning. If faced with a
challenging situation, you need to be ready for 'battle' and be prepared to
find the strength to overcome these challenges.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Ace of Swords suggests that you lack clarity around what your
true goals and aspirations are. You have a high-level understanding but have
you been able to define this in more specific terms? This card often appears
when there is a lack of clarity or complete understanding of the task at hand,
and asks you to spend some more time on clearly defining in very real terms
what it is you want in life. Set yourself some SMART goals (specific,
measurable, achievable, realistic and time-bound) so you can be really clear
on what you are working towards. Focus on the basics and do some better
planning.  
  
The Ace of Swords reversed also reflects an idea or concept which you have not
yet put into action, perhaps because you are unsure about whether or not it
will bring the results you want. You are having difficulty with the early
stages of formulating an idea, a plan or your goals. You may have too many
ideas on the go and are unable to make a decision, creating challenges with
completion.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/ace-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Two">
			<number>2</number>
			<file>51.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Two of Swords is a card of choice and of the difficulty of making a
decision. The woman in this card is blindfolded, and this may be intentionally
so, indicating that she is avoiding making a very difficult decision. Her
state of calm and relaxation may be indicative that she is trying to avoid
this important decision in order to bring about peace of mind. However, the
decision must still be made. Therefore, the appearance of the Two of Swords
indicates that you are currently being faced with a difficult decision but you
are attempting to hide from it and pretending to yourself and others that if
you ignore the decision long enough, it will go away of its own accord.
However, the decision will not go away simply by your willing it to depart.
Your conscience will eventually force you into facing your refusal to deal
directly with the situation.  
  
The blindfolded woman in this card is also an indication that you lack the
information you need to make the right decisions at this time. You may be
missing something, such as threats or potential risks, alternative solutions,
or key pieces of information. Once you are able to remove your blindfold and
see the situation for what it really is, you will be in a much better position
to determine your path forward. Research your options more widely, seek
outside opinions and feedback, and ask yourself what you are missing here. Why
is this decision so challenging to make? What extra information do you need?

</normal>
				<reversed>The Two of Swords reversed shows that you are caught between a rock and a hard
place and you are finding it incredibly difficult to make a decision about
what to do. You are really struggling to see what the right choice is as
either option will lead to negative consequences. Lay out the pros and cons of
each option that is available to you and weigh up which option will have the
most favourable outcome.  
  
The reversed Two of Swords may also indicate mental confusion as a result of
information overload. You are overwhelmed with other people's points of view
and additional, detailed information about what options are available to you.
At the end of the day, you are going to have to make a decision, so sift
through the advice and the information that is available to select only the
most relevant and helpful.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/two-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Three">
			<number>3</number>
			<file>52.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Three of Swords therefore serves as a reminder that if you can start to
see pain as a learning opportunity, life will suddenly become less painful.
You need to really get in touch with pain and sorrow. Challenges remain but
once they are no longer perceived as negative or 'bad', they lose a lot of
their impact. This card is therefore encouraging you that you have the ability
to conquer any pain that comes your way. Understand how the pain can help you
grow. If someone has betrayed you and you do not think you can ever love
again, challenge that belief. Do not be surprised when your heart emerges from
darkness, capable of loving even more than before.  
  
Similarly, the Three of Swords speaks of loss and difficulty, of sacrifice and
broken relationships. It follows the difficult decision required in the Two of
Swords, where you may be avoiding the necessity of making a tough choice. In
the Three of Swords, the choice has been made, and you are now experiencing
the consequences of our action. Often the choices make involve choosing one
good over another, or one evil over another, and thus when you have finally
made your decision, you are still left with the pain of losing the option you
have not chosen. Often, however, the pain of losing something you once valued
(such as a 'comfortable' relationship in which you are no longer growing) is
necessary in order to prepare you for a more fulfilling experience in the
future.

</normal>
				<reversed>In its reversed position, the Three of Swords indicates that you have recently
gone through a difficult patch where perhaps a relationship has ended or has
experienced challenging times, a loved one has passed, or you felt hurt from a
situation that affected you deeply. Thankfully, this time has passed and you
are on the path to recovery, realising that with behind every cloud is a
silver lining and there are indeed other things in your life which you can
feel happy about. You have reached a point where you can accept the pain and
hurt and are ready to move on.  
  
On the flipside, the reversed Three of Swords can also suggest that you are
finding it very hard to move on from a recent loss or heartbreak. This card
suggests that inside you are still suffering emotionally from a previous loss
and need to go through an emotional purging process to allow yourself freedom
from your past. You are doing your best to leave this behind and make a new
life but it is still a long journey ahead. Be careful that you are not getting
stuck in the moment of grief, and instead you are focused on leaving behind
your past and embracing new opportunities. It is always hard to bear the pain
of separation or understand why you have been inflicted with such sorrow.
Learn to accept your situation so that the healing process will not become
blocked. Allow yourself to experience the pain, give yourself the right to
grieve and release the heartache. Let it go, and then, once the upset, pain
and tears have gone, open the door to new experiences.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/three-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Four">
			<number>4</number>
			<file>53.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Four of Swords is a reminder that after every crisis and before every new
challenge, there is always a time of relaxation and contemplation. Constant
stress and tension will break even the hardest and most resilient of people
but brief periods of rest enable you to refresh your energy, concentration and
focus, ready for the next challenge. These rests should be used wisely, to
heal the body and ready the mind.  
  
The Four of Swords is also a sign that you can stop worrying, put down your
defences and take a breather from the chaos around you. For the moment there
is a truce and you can catch your breath without being attacked again.
However, bear in mind that a truce and peace are not the same thing. The Four
of Swords is a guarantee that challenges will return to your life as soon as
you are ready to face them, so make the most of the stillness and quiet you
have earned but never lose sight of the fact that the battle is not yet over,
and that there is still work to be done.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Four of Swords reversed can indicate that you are feeling restless and
wanting to do everything at once. Even if your body is telling you that you
need to rest and relax, your mind may be pushing you forward, trying to
accomplish a long list of tasks. You may be getting quite sick or stressed as
a result, so it is vital that you force yourself to pause and take it easy to
ensure that you do not become completely run down and exhausted.  
  
You may also be trying to avoid any period of contemplation or meditation on a
particular issue because you are worried about what it might bring up. You
need to return to the energy of the Three of Swords and confront the pain and
grief that exists within your heart. You need to experience that pain as it is
preventing you from being able to move on. Once you have experienced it, it
will begin to subside and you will be able to live a more fulfilling life.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/four-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Five">
			<number>5</number>
			<file>54.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Five of Swords sees you engaging in conflict or finding yourself
disagreeing with others, leading to tension and hostility. Despite thinking
you have won, you may still end up the loser because you have hurt or annoyed
others and have subsequently isolated yourself. You try to pick up the pieces
and act as if the conflict is now in the past but others have now lost faith
in you and do not want to be around you. This might be one of those times when
it feels like everyone is against you and you may lose some friends along the
way. You will need to make a decision about whether your point of view is so
important to you that it is ok to put your relationship with others in
jeopardy, or whether you can compromise and try to see eye-to-eye with others.  
  
The Five of Swords can relate to a betrayal or sneak attack by someone you
trust and do not suspect as your enemy. There may be an unfaithful partner or
a jealous person in your life who is sabotaging you behind your back. Look to
other Court cards in the reading to understand who may be working against you.
You must be very careful whom you trust at this point in time because you are
vulnerable to attack and gossip.

</normal>
				<reversed>Thus, the Five of Swords reversed suggests that you are now more open to
change. The arguing is over and you are more willing to look at the situation
with fresh eyes. You are willing to lay down your sword and begin negotiating,
honestly trying to arrive at a win-win solution rather than always knocking
heads. A return to the Four of Swords is required, where tranquillity and
peace drive your thoughts and behaviour, moving away from tension and
conflict. This is a good time to reach out to those with whom you have
recently had conflict or disagreements, and make amends.  
  
The Five of Swords reversed can sometimes indicate conflict in your life that
you have tried to walk away from but which continues to follow you. For
example, there may still be an ex in your life who is making things difficult
and who may be preventing you from moving on to new relationships. So long as
there is conflict, tension and raw emotion at play, avoid this person or
situation.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/five-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Six">
			<number>6</number>
			<file>55.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Six of Swords shows that you will need to make a regretful transition, as
a likely result of the decisions you make. You know that in order to move
forward, you must leave something important behind, and while you do this with
some regret, you know that in the long-term it is the best option for you.
There are times when you will be forced to let go of something to which you
have been attached, and the process of letting go is often quite challenging.
However, the sadness of your loss will soon be replaced by greater clarity,
bringing about a renewed acceptance of change. Do not be afraid to let go of
whatever it is that is holding you in the present or the past. Instead look to
your future and choose the best option that has the greatest long-term
potential. There are going to be some hard decisions and some compromises that
you will need to make but this is ultimately a 'rite of passage' that will
take you into a new phase of your life.  
  
More literally, the Six of Swords can indicate a trip across water (for
example, via a ferry, boat, or plane overseas). There may be some sadness in
terms of who you will need to leave behind you but you know that this trip
will do you a world of good! An example might be someone who is about to
travel on their own, leaving behind a partner who they will sorely miss. You
may also be required to make a longer-term move from one location to another,
where you will leave behind friends and family in order to explore or
experience a new territory. Again, while you will miss those you leave behind,
you will also find that you have an amazing time on your travels and will
learn so much about yourself.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Six of Swords reversed indicates that you are trying your best to move on
from the past and make the important transition that you know you need to
make. You are trying to physically and mentally move from any past experiences
which you know that have not been helping you. However, given this card is
reversed, it is clear that you are experiencing some challenges in doing this
and no matter how hard you try to leave the past behind you, it keeps catching
up with you. It is like there is something pulling you back to where you have
come from, rather than allowing you to move on to new territories. What is
hard is that there are a lot of unresolved issues from the past, which you had
hoped you could just leave behind you but they keep rearing their ugly head
and preventing you from getting to that new place of being that you really
want to be. There may also be moments when you doubt whether you are making
the right decision in leaving behind your past but this card gently encourages
you forward, reminding you that you are heading towards a better future.  
  
Similarly, the reversal of this card may suggest that you are resisting this
necessary transition. Perhaps you feel that it has been forced upon you or
that you were not included in the decision to move. For example, your partner
may be required to relocate for work and you must go along with him/her. What
is important is that you look at the benefits of the transition rather than
focusing on the drawbacks so that even if this transition is out of your
control, you can at least look forward to something and get some sort of
personal value out of it.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/six-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Seven">
			<number>7</number>
			<file>56.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Seven of Swords is a card of deception and betrayal. It indicates the
difficulty of trying to 'get away with something' undetected and unnoticed.
Often when you do something in secret, hoping that you are safe and
undiscovered, something goes awry and your secret is revealed to your
embarrassment. This card therefore urges caution when attempting to use
cunning or deception to gain an advantage over someone or something else.
There is no question that there are times in life when it is necessary to act
shrewdly or do something in secret. Perhaps you had to think on your feet and
act in a way that was not exactly all 'above board'. Perhaps you had to go
behind other people's backs in order to manifest your desires. Perhaps you
felt like you needed to cheat or take the easy way out. If acting shrewdly is
something you must do, it is essential that you do this with a clear
conscience and you are fully aware of the potential consequences of your
actions. Taking the easy path is not always the best path, and sometimes you
just have to exert a decent amount of effort to achieve what you want.  
  
The Seven of Swords indicates that you may be tempted to sneak away from a
particular situation that is not working for you any more, rather than dealing
with it head on. As you do not feel ready to deal with the issues, you are
aiming for a solution where you can just escape and not have to worry about it
all. Are you trying to run away from commitment, responsibility, hard work or
love? You may be procrastinating, letting problems slip and become worse
because you do not want to deal with them. Sometimes you just have to face
what has to be faced. So, the question is, "Is this realistic?" Will this
'escape' really accomplish what you want to and need to accomplish? Will it
address the fundamental issues at hand here? The likely answer is no, and it
may simply be an easy way out for now.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Seven of Swords is a card of mental challenges and rites of passage. The
reversal of this card shows that you are finding it difficult to take the
first step in a new direction. At times it may seem impossible that you could
create the types of changes you want as you continually come up against
setback after setback. Yet, you know in your soul, that when the timing is
right, you will be able to follow through on your dreams, releasing an old
pain from your heart.  
  
The Seven of Swords reversed suggests that you need to break free from old
habits and ways of thinking in order to overcome the blockages that currently
stand in your way. You need to accept what is happening to you and act on it,
rather than trying to escape. You need to do things differently, releasing
yourself from past behaviours or limiting beliefs so that you can move forward
in your life. Do not become trapped into thinking that you can only do certain
things with which you are familiar. Expand your consideration set to broader
horizons.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/seven-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Eight">
			<number>8</number>
			<file>57.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Eight of Swords is often a sign that it is best not to make any important
decisions at this point because your thinking has been limited and constrained
by self-imposed boundaries. You are struggling to see a situation for what it
is and have been lead to believe certain things that may or may not be true.
There are choices available but first you must be within the right mindset to
know which option to choose. This means releasing the bindings and the
blindfold to see the situation from a different, less imposing angle. There
may also be too many ideas running through your head, thus it is best to wait
until you feel more secure and certain about a situation before making
important decisions and taking action.  
  
The woman in the Eight of Swords is often seen as powerless. She has
surrendered her power to an unknown entity, thus rendering herself completely
powerless. She has become the victim and is now waiting to be rescued. If you
see part of this woman in yourself, then it is imperative you take back your
power and personal accountability and open your eyes to the options that lie
in front of you. The fact is that you do have options, even if you do not like
those options. This is fine, so long as you accept that you do indeed have
options and you do not have to be the victim here.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Eight of Swords reversed indicates that you have come through a difficult
time and you are becoming more open to change and self-acceptance. You have
been able to reflect on what did and did not work in the past and have changed
your perspective and approach. You acknowledge that you do indeed have
options, and you are refusing to play the role of 'the victim', taking greater
accountability for where you are in life.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/eight-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Nine">
			<number>9</number>
			<file>58.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Nine of Swords is the card of fear and nightmares, and has an apparently
negative 'feel' to it. However, the troubles alluded to in the Nine of Swords
are primarily of a psychological nature and do not necessarily indicate
suffering in your external reality. That is, it is what is inside your mind
that is creating the fear and anxiety, not your actual circumstances. Your
experience of the world is greatly influenced by our expectations, desires,
and fears, and therefore you are largely the creator of your own world, and
your attitudes determine how you experience that world.  
  
The Nine of Swords can also indicate that you are being incredibly hard on
yourself, putting yourself down or engaging in negative self-talk. For every
mistake you make, you blame yourself and become worked up and angry at
yourself for messing up again. So, when the Nine of Swords appears in a
reading, ask yourself why you are being so hard on yourself, how are you
putting yourself down or what is the source of your depression? What can you
do to make yourself feel better? You may need to make a more conscious effort
to quit the negative self-talk and replace it with positive reinforcement for
a job well done.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Nine of Swords is about worry, anxiety and not being able to sleep because
your thoughts are running at one hundred miles an hour. Reversed, the Nine of
Swords indicates that you are working yourself up and becoming incredibly
stressed and anxious when, really, this does not have to be a complicated
issue. You have a tendency to get very worked up about how bad a situation
appears, losing sight of what it is really happening and what opportunities
are available to you. What is needed here is for you to stop and objectively
examine the reality of the situation. Bring yourself back to earth by
uncovering your fears and anxieties and working to reduce the impact of those
fears and anxieties on your life. Know that it is going to be ok, no matter
what.  
  
The Nine of Swords reversed also suggests that your worry and despair may
actually be causing you harm. The more you worry about something, the more
likely it is you will manifest your worst nightmares. Do not let this
nightmare become your reality! Take a deep breath and realise that life is not
as bad as it seems and that the more you worry, the more harm you are doing to
yourself.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/nine-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Ten">
			<number>10</number>
			<file>59.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Ten of Swords usually symbolises a sudden and unexpected failure or
disaster, whereby a power beyond your control crushes you without warning or
mercy. Sometimes you will be able to alter the course of this impending
disaster but most of the time you will simply have to let go and take the hit.
This card can also indicate a time when you have been backstabbed or betrayed
by someone you thought you could trust. You feel incredibly hurt and shocked
by such a betrayal.  
  
The Ten of Swords also indicates a difficult experience of endings, loss, pain
or release. However, the saving grace is that you have a new awareness and a
positive sense of relief that the difficulty and pain will soon be over and
will evolve into something new. As with all endings there will be a new
beginning, a rebirth, and a rejuvenation of the spirit. So, while this card
may seem negative at first glance, it is a card of hope and an indication that
your troubles will not be permanent.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Ten of Swords reversed indicates a painful ending which must occur for
there to be growth and regeneration. The suit of Swords is the suit of
thoughts, plans, and attitudes, and this card is very appropriate in the area
of mental transformations. This card indicates that there will be a forceful
re-evaluation or elimination of your previous attitudes about life, your views
about yourself and what is important, and possibly your plans for the future.
Despite the initial trauma and torment associated with this change, the
imposed re-evaluation can be a very positive thing. It is important to
understand that while the means of your demise may not seem reasonable or
fair, your previous thoughts and attitudes really need to change in order for
you to reach a better place in your life. Rather than dwelling on the painful
ending, it is important to look ahead and realise how these events free you up
to completely reshape your life and choose a new direction for yourself.  
  
Sometimes, the Ten of Swords reversed may reflect fear of ruin, even if that
ruin as not yet occurred. You are always be thinking of the worst-case
scenario and planning for the worst, even if it does not happen. This is only
creating unnecessary fear and anxiety for you, and it is important that you
return to the energy of the Nine of Swords and run a reality check as to
whether things are as bad as they seem.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/ten-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Page">
			<number/>
			<file>60.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Page of Swords reflects an abundance of energy, passion and enthusiasm.
You cannot wait to get started on a new project or an idea, and to share that
with others. You start all new projects, ventures and journeys with a huge
amount of energy and excitement. The challenge, however, is whether you can
keep it up! As with all Pages, the beginning always looks promising but
something else is needed in order to maintain the pace.  
  
The downside of the Page of Swords is the turbulent nature of intellectual
discovery and inspiration unchecked by experience or wisdom. This Page seems
to be either on the defensive, protecting his ideas, or on the offensive,
looking for some victim of the double-edged sword of his mind. Perhaps he is
seeking a confrontation in the intellectual sense or has the desire to prove
himself mentally superior to others. The trouble is that he does not yet have
the maturity to express himself in a way that is always constructive, and may
come across as oppositional or just too 'in your face'.

</normal>
				<reversed>Reversed, the Page of Swords can suggest you are acting hastily, without
thinking things through properly. You have a lot of energy behind you to get
things moving but the way you are going about it is not an effective use of
your energy. Tackle things one at a time, rather than trying to deal with
everything at once. This will lead to more meaningful outcomes.  
  
The reversed Page of Swords can also be all talk and no action. You have to be
very careful of making promises that you know you cannot keep, or saying
things that you later regret. Before making a specific promise or commitment,
ensure that you can and will deliver on it in order to maintain your integrity
and reputation. Also, be wary of other people's commitments to you and put in
place measures to ensure that they will deliver on what they promise to
deliver. This reversed Page can be a bit of a 'know-it-all' and may be trying
to impress you with big stories about his past and his achievements (which you
later find out are big exaggerations of the truth!).

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/page-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Knight">
			<number/>
			<file>61.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>When we are obsessed by an idea and wish to manifest that idea, we are often
so blinded by the desire for its fulfilment that we fail to see the
difficulties we may encounter or the consequences of our actions. The Knight
of Swords is a powerful figure full of life and energy who needs to be
balanced with a realisation of responsibility and compassion. Once he has set
forth on his journey, there is no stopping him! He does not see, nor care
about, any upcoming challenges, risks or dangers, and instead moves forward
with his strong intent to succeed and win. On the positive side, this card
shows great ambition, determination and strength to succeed no matter what. On
the negative side, however, he can be blind to potential challenges and
consequences of his actions, and may charge forth into a dangerous territory
without any foresight or preparation. He may also neglect to understand the
needs of others as he fervently pursues his own goals.  
  
The Knight of Swords often reflects a time when you are embarking on a new
project or idea and there really is no stopping you. You have had this sudden
burst of energy that is propelling you forward and inspiring you to take quick
action to manifest your goals. You are ready to overcome any problem,
challenge or obstacle that is in your path. How could anything stand in your
way if you are this focused and this committed to your goal? However, you may
be prone to rushing things or cutting corners in order to get a job done.
Sometimes this works for you but other times it does not. For example, using
low cost providers will help you get the job done quickly and cheaply but
quality may suffer in the long-term and you may consume more time fixing their
work. Also, ensure that you keep others on side, particularly if they are part
of your longer-term success. You might be all fired up and ready to go but if
your colleagues, partner, friends, or family are not, then you are likely to
run into trouble later down the track.

</normal>
				<reversed>This reversed Knight is incredibly impatient, impulsive and bursting with
energy. This person has so much energy but so little direction that this
results in them making rash decisions and pulling down others with them. Their
thoughts are scattered and all over the place. They are likely to be very
disorganised, flippant and unpredictable. If you encounter this type of
person, you need to be very wary and make sure that you do not get caught up
in all the hype and energy that surrounds them. It will be easily done for
this person is a greater talker and is full of ideas and thoughts about future
opportunities. Do not get sucked in to their whirlwind of activity and energy!  
  
The Knight of Swords reversed indicates that you need to go it alone in order
to build up valuable life experience and maturity. As you search for freedom
and independence, it is likely you will make mistakes on your way due to your
reckless and impatient nature but this is all part of the journey. This card
can often reflect a rebellious teenager who is fighting for their own
independence, and the parents who need to allow that teenager to make the
mistakes and to be accountable for their actions.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/knight-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Queen">
			<number/>
			<file>62.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Queen of Swords is a sign that you need to be independent in thought and
in judgement. You must use your unbiased intelligence in order to make a
judgement of a particular situation, drawing upon every piece of information
and fact that you have gathered along the way. Empathy or compassion towards
others may distract you from the task at hand, so it is important that you
think with your head and not with your heart at this particular time. Do not
let emotion get in the way. Rather, use fact and logic to make your decisions.  
  
The Queen of Swords also has an innate ability to tell it like it is. She is a
quick thinker and highly perceptive, and as such, she can cut through the
noise and confusion to get straight to the point. There is certainly no
'beating about the bush', or 'softening' of her comments, opinions and
thoughts. She is upfront and honest about her opinions, and expects the same
from others. The best way to interact with the Queen of Swords, therefore, is
to remain as impartial as possible, and to present your thoughts and opinions
concisely and honestly.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Queen of Swords reversed indicates that currently you may be thinking more
with your heart than your head. You may be very emotionally involved in a
particular situation or issue but this may be distorting your perception of
the situation at hand. You need to use your head a little bit more to
understand what is happening and read the signals more accurately. Look at
your situation objectively and think with your head and not your heart as this
may give you a better picture of the situation and help you evaluate what you
need to do next.  
  
Similarly, the reversed Queen of Swords suggests that relationships are
clouding your usually clear vision. You need to refocus your goals or
direction, yet you are hesitating due to a desire not to disturb the positive
balance and harmony of your relationships with others. At the end of the day,
you need to be more hard-edged, confident and assertive in order to be
successful. Clear sight and analysis, objective weighing of options and ideas
for the future, and even carefully considering but not necessarily choosing,
the alternatives are essential right now.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/queen-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="King">
			<number/>
			<file>63.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The King of Swords suggests that you need to adopt a very stern but fair role.
You have clarity of mind and can perceive the truth right now, so you must
take the lead with providing an objective point of view. You are well-
positioned to judge your situation appropriately and identify the limiting
behaviours that are getting the way. This is a time when you need to leave
emotions out of it, and remain as objective and rational as possible. You may
need to reason with others and be quite direct about what you are observing.
You may be concerned that you are not being particularly caring or sympathetic
but at this point in time, this detachment is what is needed most.  
  
Similarly, the King of Swords encourages you to use your logic and intellect
to navigate your path ahead. You will need to get to the heart of the matter,
make firm and well-researched decisions, and ensure that you are firm but fair
in your dealings with others. You need to be able to take any situation, look
at it with total impartiality, and then come to a decision that is both fair
and insightful.

</normal>
				<reversed>The King of Swords reversed can suggest the misuse of one's mental power,
authority, and drive. The reversed King of Swords represents manipulation and
persuasion in order to fulfil selfish needs. He is a very intelligent older
male (or sometimes female) who likes to show off to others about how smart he
is by using big words or talking about topics about which no-one else knows.
He may also be very cutting in his words, critical of others, and stern in his
manner. This card may represent a person in your life or even yourself. You
need to be wary of this type of person because, although he/she may be
charming and intelligent, they can do only harm. They have only their personal
interests in mind and will do whatever they can to achieve these interests,
even if it means stepping on others.  
  
Similarly, the King of Swords reversed can be quite a tyrant and a 'loose
cannon'. He is prone to aggression and angry outbursts, particularly if you
make him look bad or challenge his authority. He is not pleasant to be around
and is likely to leave you feeling demoralised and put down.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-swords/king-of-swords/</source>
		</card>
	</suit>
	<suit name="Pentacles" affinity="Earth">
		<card name="Ace">
			<number>1</number>
			<file>64.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Ace of Pentacles is symbolic of wealth, not just in the financial sense
but also in a more holistic sense. You may see new opportunities come your way
to generate a new source of income, or you may be lucky enough to receive a
financial gift or windfall. On a broader level, this Ace indicates abundance
in all areas of your life and a general feeling that you are indeed blessed
and deserving of everything that comes your way. Operate by the Law of
Attraction, and send out positive energy into the Universe so that you may
receive abundance in return.  
  
The Ace of Pentacles is about manifestation of your goals, and that you are
moving into a more positive state of mind about what you are capable of
achieving. Your ideas are ready to be turned into something tangible. Figure
out what will work and make it a reality. Thus, the Ace of Pentacles sees you
starting to map out how exactly you will achieve your goals, by creating
targeted action plans and getting those actions underway. There are
opportunities that are becoming available to you that will help you to
manifest your goals and realise your inner potential, whilst at the same time
generate some level of income and financial support. You are beginning to see
that the world is indeed your oyster and that through careful planning, you
can manifest your true goals and desires.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Ace of Pentacles indicates a time when you try to manifest your
goals but you do not get very far along due to delays and other impediments to
your plans. If your success is limited, then you may need to re-evaluate and
modify your plans and proposed approach. Your goals may also need to be re-
aligned to something more realistic. Financial or other professional advice
may be needed to help you get back on track.  
  
The reversed Ace of Pentacles can indicate corruption, greed and taking what
one has not earned. Be careful that you are not being overly opportunistic and
exploiting others as you strive towards higher profits and earnings. You may
also be blinded by an obsession for greater financial accumulation and wealth,
at the expense of other areas of your life.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/ace-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Two">
			<number>2</number>
			<file>65.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Two of Pentacles serves as a reminder to remain alert, agile and patient
as you attempt to juggle your family, your friends, work, finances, health and
new challenges. You need to be very clear on your priorities and where you
want to invest your time and energy. There is a tendency to be distracted by
day-to-day affairs and general busy-ness, so prioritising your activities and
carefully managing your time is essential.  
  
The Two of Pentacles brings you back down to earth and reminds you to not only
focus on your broader life goals but to also make sure your day-to-day affairs
are in order. This is a card of good time management and financial management,
ensuring that your bills are paid on time, that you keep a record of all your
appointments and daily commitments, etc. It may sound tedious having to focus
your attention on these more mundane issues but this card reminds you that
sometimes getting on top of your daily affairs is as important as pursuing
your broader life goals.

</normal>
				<reversed>In your day-to-day life, the reversed Two of Pentacles suggests that you are
very busy and at times you struggle to manage your activities and commitments.
You may also be struggling to manage your finances and to stay on top of
paying bills and keeping abridge of other financial commitments. The stress is
getting to you and you are becoming easily overwhelmed by your
responsibilities. Therefore, this card encourages you to become more organised
and more planned in your approach. You may need to bring a little more
structure to your day-to-day affairs, through budgets, 'to do' lists, forward
planning or diary and effective time management. Life is certainly a juggling
act, so make sure you are on top of everything you need to be!  
  
The reversed Two of Pentacles can be a clear indicator that you are not
managing your work and family commitments. It is more than likely you are
investing most of your time in work, neglecting your family or your partner.
While you may be able to get away with a couple of late nights at work, there
will come a time when enough is enough and you will need to make a choice.
Something has got to give!

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/two-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Three">
			<number>3</number>
			<file>66.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The message of the Three of Pentacles is one of encouragement. If you continue
to work toward the fulfilment of your dreams and do not allow disillusionment
to dampen your enthusiasm, ultimately you will experience prosperity and
success in your goals. You need to do work that is satisfying to you and that
you can be truly proud of. What new beginnings are you experiencing in the
material realm? Is there some project or creative venture you have been
putting off because of fear of failure? The Three of Pentacles indicates that
dreams can be made real with persistence, determination, and effort.  
  
At the core of the Three of Pentacles is the notion of teamwork and
collaboration. In the card, we see a young mason working hard on building part
of the cathedral. The two monks enter, with their worldly knowledge and
spiritual understanding to bring a new perspective to the mason's work. Even
though their backgrounds, experience levels and knowledge is very different,
they are able to come together to share their expertise in a way that creates
synergy and improved results. There is no 'us and them' or any sense of
superiority. Rather, each person has something unique to offer and is willing
to learn from others involved in the project. Everyone is getting the job done
together and is contributing to the group through effective listening and
sharing. This is a positive card to see when teamwork, collaboration and
cooperation are required between parties with different levels of experience.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Three of Pentacles can indicate a lack of teamwork, whereby
people are acting in competition with each other and trying to appear the most
knowledgeable. You may be trying to work collaboratively with others but there
is an increasing level of tension as each individual tries to exert power or
control over the group, thus negatively impacting the harmony of the people
involved.  
  
The Three of Pentacles reversed signifies that you are seeking more respect in
the workplace. You have had to be polite and listen to the opinions and
feedback of your superiors but now you seem to be growing restless with always
taking the advice, rather than giving it. You want to work in an environment
where you have the chance to voice your own opinion and be heard, where you
are seen as the expert or the leader. You may also be seeking new colleagues
who bring with them new knowledge, so as to create a more synergistic team
environment.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/three-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Four">
			<number>4</number>
			<file>67.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Four of Pentacles generates both positive and negative perceptions. On the
one hand, this card signifies that you have accomplished many of your goals
and have attained great material wealth in the process. However, on the other
hand, there is a risk that you will come to value only material wealth, thus
becoming possessive and/or greedy in ensuring that no-one else takes away your
wealth.  
  
Sometimes, the Four of Pentacles can indicate an inflexible attitude that is
resistant to change. You have already established a way of living that now
works for you, so why change? Change appears to be a threat to your certainty,
safety and security, and may place you at risk of losing all that is important
to you. Any suggestion of doing things differently is therefore going to be
met with resistance for fear of how it will impact your personal sense of
security. Thus, you are more likely to favour tradition and tried-and-tested
ways of doing things, rather than taking any risks at this point.

</normal>
				<reversed>Reversed, the conservatism of the Four of Pentacles has turned to greed and
stinginess. You are haunted by a fear of poverty that compels you to be
materialistic. You are extremely defensive and self-protective materially and
emotionally, fearful of opening up and trusting other people. You are very
reluctant to spend money and you are keeping a very tight rein on your cash.
On the flipside, you may be spending too much money and need to get a better
hold of your financial resources.  
  
The Four of Pentacles reversed asks you to loosen your hold on your need for
security and stability and step outside your comfort zone. While it will feel
a bit shaky at the start, this is an important step in your personal
development.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/four-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Five">
			<number>5</number>
			<file>68.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Five of Pentacles typically points to a time of financial strife, poverty
and adversity and indicates that you have suffered a significant financial
loss or failure. This card shows the many faces of material misfortune and
lack, including loss of funds, general poverty, illness, unemployment, and
solitude. If you have suffered a loss, know that there are people around you
who are willing to help. There is always a solution and always a way out, so
either open your eyes and go to it, or close your eyes and let the inner light
guide you.  
  
On a psychological level, the Five of Pentacles may indicate difficulty with
your relationship to money and material things. If money becomes the primary
motivating force in life and the gauge by which you judge your worth, the lack
of it may produce anxiety and a sense of being excluded from the good things
money can provide. For example, if you are unfortunate enough to encounter
financial difficulties such as the loss of employment or an investment gone
belly-up, you may fall into the trap of losing faith in your ability to
recreate a positive financial situation for yourself. Therefore, you should
not only consider your actual financial circumstances but also your attitudes
toward money. What fears do you have around money and wealth? Are you anxious
about never having enough, or do you have faith in your ability to manifest
what you need to live a prosperous, fulfilled life no matter what your
circumstances? Often wealth is based as much on your psychological state as
your actual financial state.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Five of Pentacles reversed indicates an end to difficult times,
particularly if you have recently suffered a major financial loss or job loss.
You may find new sources of income, a new job, or someone has offered to help
you out while you get back on your feet. You may be starting to feel as if
life is worth living again and starting to regain your self-confidence.
Finally you can see a way out of your financial difficulties and your hope is
being renewed.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/five-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Six">
			<number>6</number>
			<file>69.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Six of Pentacles is a card representing being in harmony with your money.
The amount that comes in and the amount that flows out are in balance, and you
are thankful for what you have without being grasping of it, and happy to
share with others in need. This card is also about charity. You may either be
the wealthy man in this card, giving away his wealth, or the beggars,
gratefully receiving what the man has to offer.  
  
If you are the beggars in the Six of Pentacles, then you may be the recipient
of someone else's charitable activities. This will help you to get back on
your feet and to eventually repay the charitable organisation or individual,
either with your time or your restored wealth. You will also need to identify
ways in which you can become more self-sufficient in the long run. The risk of
accepting charity is that you become dependent on it and cannot look after
yourself. Be mindful that you are not becoming submissive or noticeably
'desperate' as a result of the charity that someone else is providing you.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Six of Pentacles reversed suggests a one-way street in terms of charity.
You may have lent money to a friend or given someone a favour but, in this
instance, do not expect the money to be repaid or the favour to be returned.
Or, you may expect it to be repaid but it never is. With this in mind, be
careful about who you lend your money to, especially if you yourself are in
financial trouble. While a generous spirit is a wonderful quality, you need to
ensure that you are able to support yourself whilst helping others. You may
have a tendency to spend or give away more than you can afford to.  
  
The Six of Pentacles reversed sometimes reflects the selfish side of charity.
In some cases, people give to others not for the benefit of the other but for
the benefit of themselves. Be careful that you are not trying to prove to
others that you are generous because you can give to the poor or the needy.
Aim to give selflessly rather than selfishly.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/six-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Seven">
			<number>7</number>
			<file>70.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Seven of Pentacles shows that you have a strong desire to invest in those
things that will provide long-term benefit. You understand the value of
putting in time and energy now for longer-term rewards, and you are not
necessarily looking for 'quick wins' as such. You also want to make sure that
you are focusing your attention on the right areas that will give you the
biggest 'bang for your buck', instead of wasting time on areas that will not
deliver any value. You have a long-term view and you are focused on
sustainability of results.  
  
Similarly, if you are planning for the future, the Seven of Pentacles shows
that you are taking a long-term view and you are assessing where you can best
invest your time and energy for the maximum output. You do not want to keep
putting your heart and soul into something if you are not getting the rewards
for it, and no doubt, you have started to see that there are some areas in
your life that are just become energy-sappers but without the reward.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Seven of Pentacles suggests that your efforts may be scattered at
this time and you are starting to question whether or not you are investing in
the right areas. You may be outlaying some initial money on things that will
not actually deliver results. So, the opportunity here is to examine your
current and planned investments (both financial and time), and make sure that
you are going to see a return on those investments. Use a prioritisation
system to ensure that you do not waste time and money on areas that will not
deliver results.  
  
Similarly, the Seven of Pentacles reversed indicates that even though you may
continue to invest a lot of energy into a specific situation, you may not reap
the rewards you are looking for. As such, this card calls on you to prioritise
your activities very carefully. You need to do a cost-benefit analysis on the
major tasks involved to bring your project to fruition as there are certainly
a number of tasks that are currently taking a lot of your time and energy but
are not bearing the rewards you are seeking. Take stock of what you still need
to do and focus only on those things that will get you to where you want to
be. You may find that there are a lot of things that you get involved in that
are just not value-add. For example, email and meetings are huge time wasters
if not used effectively. Try to get down to the 20% of tasks that deliver 80%
of the value, and focus on these, rather than investing your time in tasks
that do not deliver any results.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/seven-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Eight">
			<number>8</number>
			<file>71.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Eight of Pentacles suggests you are working away at the finer details of
the various aspects of your life, in an effort to continuously improve your
situation. You may be unhappy with your current state and you know you need to
make some important changes in your life to increase your overall
satisfaction. This card is a really positive sign that you are committed to
making those changes and to ensuring that you give yourself the best possible
chance. Overall, this is a very hard-working and conscientious energy that is
present in your life.  
  
The Eight of Pentacles is encouragement to keep doing what you are doing as it
will eventually lead to success. Yes, it requires a lot of dedication, focus
and patience but as each day passes and as you stay true to your values and
beliefs, you get a little closer to your goal. It may not be as apparent as
you may like but events are unfolding that will lead you to the right path.
Continue working on yourself, too, and making ongoing improvements and
adjustments to ensure that you are the best person you can be.

</normal>
				<reversed>Reversed, the Eight of Pentacles can reflect that your attention to detail is
actually getting in the way of innovation and change. The Eight of Pentacles
is perfection in a self-contained world, a world that needs nothing but
perfect pentacles, one after another. But what if the rules change? What if
you are called upon to do something completely different to the task at hand
or you need to change your focus? This may send you into a tailspin! If you
need to take a risk, or to shift gears, the reversed Eight of Pentacles shows
that your perfectionism has become a barrier to your success. You will have to
let go of the smoothness and predictability of doing what you have mastered,
and be willing to make a Fool of yourself all over again.  
  
Often, the reversed Eight of Pentacles reversed suggests that you are working
very hard on something but it is not leading to the desired outcome, leading
to frustration and disappointment with the lack of success and progress.
Sometimes, we can focus in on improving a part of ourselves or trying to fix
something, only to find that all that effort is just going on the wrong
things. You may be honing in on minute details that are not important to the
overall workings of your life. Instead, you need to look at the bigger picture
and ask yourself whether this is the right direction for you at this time. How
can you bring your attention out of the detail and to the overall picture
here? Are you working on the right things, or is there a major part that you
are missing? Return to the energy of the Seven of Pentacles and re-prioritise
and invest in those activities that will lead to the greatest return.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/eight-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Nine">
			<number>9</number>
			<file>72.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Nine of Pentacles is about enjoying the good life and the fruits of your
labour. You have worked hard to get here, so now, sit back and relax and enjoy
some of life's luxuries. You deserve it! Do not be afraid to splurge, indulge
or pamper yourself, particularly if it is as a reward for all of your hard
work. Treat yourself to a special occasion, to simply celebrate the journey
you have been on to achieve your goals and to re-energise yourself for the
next phase. You are close to reaching completion, so acknowledge this and then
prepare for what will come after.  
  
Sometimes, however, the Nine of Pentacles can indicate that you are close to
reaching your goal but you have not yet made it. So, as a result, you may want
to stick to your program and continue sacrificing until you have reached that
goal. You are showing great self-discipline and self-control to ensure you get
to where you want to be.

</normal>
				<reversed>Similarly, the reversed Nine of Pentacles suggests that you may need to
release some of your focus on needing to sustain particular income and a
particular standard of living, especially if this is coming in the way of
other life priorities such as family or relationships. You may think you need
the best of everything but really, all you need is your family and loved ones
around you. Do not be afraid to take a cut to your income for a short time or
to reduce your hours at work, even if this means that you have to eat rice and
beans each night for a week to make up for it! It is important that you are
focused on what is most important to you. Finances may need to come second and
while you need to at least have food on the table, there may be some areas
where you can cut back and reduce your dependence on material wealth.  
  
On the other hand, the Nine of Pentacles reversed shows that you want to be
able to lead a luxurious life but there is something getting in the way. For
example, part of you knows you deserve a beautiful home but another part of
you doubts yourself and whether or not you can truly afford it or whether you
are going too far and splurging. You want to be surrounded by beauty but you
also do not want to be dependent on material possessions for your satisfaction
and fulfilment. You do not want to be seen as spending your money frivolously,
and so you are reluctant to invest in 'luxury'.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/nine-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Ten">
			<number>10</number>
			<file>73.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>As a Ten, the Ten of Pentacles is such a great sign that despite challenges
and setbacks along the way, you will finally reach a point of completion and
accomplishment in your journey. This sense of accomplishment is likely to be
as a result of an improved career path, more solid financial reserves, a
stable home environment and a possible committed and long-term relationship.
This is one of those cards that shows that everything will eventually come
together in a wonderful way and you will feel highly successful and proud of
everything you have achieved. You will also feel compelled to share this
success with others to ensure that they are also well cared for.  
  
This card reminds me of the wealthy retired father figure who can now finally
relax and enjoy his family and his home. He has worked incredibly hard over
his lifetime in order to build up wealth, prosperity and security. He now has
the financial reserves to share with his family to ensure that they are well
supported now and in the future, which in turn leaves him feeling happy and
content with his ability to 'provide'.

</normal>
				<reversed>Upright, the Ten of Pentacles shows a beautiful picture of a family within a
huge castle. The 'man of the house' looks so happy to have finally
accomplished everything that he has in life and is glad that he can now
provide for his family for many years to come. This is one of those ultimate
commitment cards often associated with marriage, financial success and
established families. Reversed, however, it suggests that there is something
getting in the way of this picture. The stability and security of the family
unit, the marriage or the financials has been undermined and there is no
longer that feeling of stability. In some cases, it can mean that a marriage
has come to an end very recently and it is now going through a process of
divestment. In other cases, it can mean that this is a temporary state of flux
and there is still the possibility that it can get back on track.  
  
Reversed, the Ten of Pentacles is about failure on a financial level. This
card indicates financial loss, problems with investments, and lack of
resources. Despite a lot of time and effort, there seems to be many
limitations to future success as a result of a poor foundation. In some cases,
this card represents the problems of money, such as fears about finances and
quarrels over property, as finances become an impediment to the enjoyment of
life. It could indicate that you are beset with financial burdens and
responsibilities.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/ten-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Page">
			<number/>
			<file>74.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Page of Pentacles has the desire to learn all things. He is dedicated to
knowledge and the attainment of wisdom and new skills. He is devoted to all in
which he is engaged and he has great concentration in his interests and
pursuits. Thus, the appearance of this card suggests that success will come to
you after you have mastered new skills and have set your mind to achieving
specific, tangible goals. You may need to consider further study, expanding
your skill sets at work, or learning completely new ways of doing things. Do
not be afraid to be the apprentice again, even if you are a master of another
domain. Think of those 70-year-olds who enthusiastically start a University
degree! The more skills you bring to your portfolio, the more goals and dreams
you can achieve.  
  
Sometimes, the Page of Pentacles can represent a young person who has an
entrepreneurial spirit. This person may be eager to attain wealth by pursuing
a new business idea, by learning new skills or by applying themselves to a new
situation. This Page might be young but there is also great enthusiasm,
commitment, dedication and a strong sense of responsibility to see the project
through.

</normal>
				<reversed>Upright, the Page of Pentacles is about manifesting your dreams and goals.
When this card is reversed, it can indicate that there are current blockages
standing in the way of you achieving those goals. It may be that you have not
planned sufficiently, or that you have become lazy and complacent and have
lost sight of your goal. You may also be too busy daydreaming about new dreams
and goals, without having taken any action on your original dreams and goals.
So, you need to review your goals and think again about why you were
originally motivated to achieve them. Think about what it will be like once
you achieve that goal, and become re-committed to your objectives and the
actions required to make your dreams a reality.  
  
The reversed Page of Pentacles can also indicate that you are focusing on
short-term pleasures and desires rather than sustainable and long-term goals.
You will need to move beyond material satisfaction and towards what will bring
you sustainable happiness and fulfilment.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/page-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Knight">
			<number/>
			<file>75.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Knight of Pentacles works in a very methodical and rigorous manner. Though
his visions may not be earth-shattering, and his methods are certainly not
original, the Knight of Pentacles sees that everything he undertakes will meet
with nothing but success. He has the patience to accomplish all his tasks and
he is incredibly reliable due to his sense of responsibility and commitment.
As a court card, the Knight of Pentacles may represent a part of yourself,
someone in your life or an event.  
  
There is a certain element of perfectionism associated with the Knight of
Pentacles. You are meticulous in your approach and you make sure that
everything is planned and executed down to the finest detail to create overall
success. You will never leave a job half done. It is essential to you that you
complete all assigned tasks and projects to a certain standard and that you
follow through on your promises.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Knight of Pentacles reversed is about feeling stuck in a routine and a
repetitive pattern of behaviour. Life is becoming mundane and boring, and you
are beginning to crave change or any sort of spontaneity. To free yourself
from this repetition, aim to do things differently each time and bring some
spontaneity into your life.  
  
The Knight of Pentacles reversed can also suggest there are practical matters
in your life that you have chosen to ignore recently. Mundane activities such
as home upkeep, money matters, business relationships, and moving forward in
your career have been left by the wayside as you focus on more exciting or
important opportunities. Depending on what is on your plate currently, you may
want to make more time to get your life in order, or you may continue to focus
on more pressing or important priorities.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/knight-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Queen">
			<number/>
			<file>76.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Queen of Pentacles is a very 'motherly' card, expressing practical energy.
She is the original Earth Mother. She shows her love for others by cooking,
cleaning, keeping a warm and inviting home and bringing in a decent income to
support the family financially. She is also able to work a full-time job, take
care of the children, keep the house clean, and still have time to read the
business section of the newspaper. She probably has her very own bank account
or investment portfolio that nobody else knows about. She strives to create a
warm and secure environment for her family and loved ones, and gives love and
support freely.  
  
The Queen of Pentacles may represent a mother figure in your life who can
provide you with loving support and nurturing to help you get through the
influences of your past. She may be a teacher, a counsellor, a mentor, or
someone who you are very close to. Alternatively, she may represent a part of
yourself, particularly if you are investing a lot of yourself into nurturing
and caring for others and creating an established and comfortable lifestyle.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Queen of Pentacles reversed sees you becoming very consumed in your work.
You may be placing your career before your family or your relationships, and
this is having a detrimental impact. Of course, this may be ok on a temporary
basis but you need to assess its long-term impact. To rebalance your life, you
may find a release by returning to a favourite nature spot (a forest, beach or
mountain) and allowing yourself to take in this fresh, natural energy.  
  
Similarly, the Queen of Pentacles reversed can suggest that you are feeling
worried about whether you can be financially independent, while also still
maintaining your family connections. You may be concerned that if you invest
in your career or financial well-being, you might not have enough energy to
invest in your family. Sometimes, you just cannot do everything and you will
need to make some choices.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/queen-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="King">
			<number/>
			<file>77.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The King of Pentacles is a lot like King Midas. Everything he touches turns to
gold. He is a shining example of financial stability, with wealth and
experience coming easily to him and to share with everyone around him. This is
a man who has reached the pinnacle of his financial power and influence and is
able to rest assured of his continued prosperity. He is no longer required to
struggle to achieve what he desires, like the Page and the Knight, and is able
to accomplish anything he wants because he has already proven himself.  
  
Thus, the King of Pentacles often indicates the final fulfilment of a creative
task, business venture, or investment. Through diligence, responsibility and
attention to detail you have achieved great things and can finally say that
you have completed your task or attained your goal. You can now enjoy all that
you have accomplished and the successes you have created. You have created a
richness of life, not just financially but also spiritually, which will set
you up very well for the future.

</normal>
				<reversed>The King of Pentacles reversed may show some possible downsides or character
traits to be aware of. He can show an excessive interest in material things,
including good food, wine or sex. These can be fun but can also be taken to an
extreme. He can also be very stubborn and traditional about some things, which
could be exasperating. He also expects to be King of his castle, and is
possessive about his home and things.  
  
The King of Pentacles reversed is a man who will do anything for money. He is
impressed by other people's status and social position and will readily say
'yes' to any requests from those above him. At the same time, he dismisses
those who do not hold the same level of authority and status, and may come
across as a 'snob' to others. He is constantly name-dropping and trying to
prove himself by bragging about the people he knows. This reversed King can be
either a workaholic or an extremely lazy man who expects others to look after
him financially. He may care only for his possessions, and uses other people
to gain them. He may be someone who marries for money, leaving the person only
when he has gone through all of their resources.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/minor-arcana/suit-of-pentacles/king-of-pentacles/</source>
		</card>
	</suit>
	<suit name="Major Arcana" affinity="Concepts" nosuitname="true">
		<card name="The Fool">
			<number>0</number>
			<file>0.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Fool Tarot card is a card of potential, new beginnings and innocence. This
Tarot card shows the highest potential for your life, reaching a state of
renewal and new beginnings, where each day is an adventure and each moment is
lived to the fullest. The Fool card represents the beginning of all creativity
and a desire to accomplish new goals (or to, at least, start the process of
working towards those goals). The Fool indicates that anything can happen and
the opportunities are just waiting to be taken advantage of.  
  
In a Tarot reading, the Fool represents the need to set forth on a new
journey, one that is completely unknown and will take you to uncharted
territories. The Fool is all about new experiences, personal growth,
development and adventure. The Fool Tarot card asks you to take a 'leap of
faith' and to trust in the Universe in that if you begin a new journey, you
will find success. This Fool lives a carefree life, free from worry and
anxiety. He does not seem to mind if he does not really know what lies ahead.

</normal>
				<reversed>Reversed, the Fool Tarot card suggests that you may be acting in total
disregard of the consequences of your actions and indeed acting 'the fool'.
You are trying to live 'in the moment' rather than planning ahead. You are
acting recklessly, wanting to break free of the usual routine in order to
'find yourself' but doing it in a way that completely disregards others.  
  
The Fool reversed cautions you about potentially being taken advantage of or
entering into a deal where you do not fully understand the consequences of
your decisions. If you are offered an opportunity that seems too good to be
true then it probably is. It is really important that you do almost a 'due
diligence' on the opportunities presented to you to ensure that you are making
the right choice and not simply going with the most enticing offer at the
time. Be prepared for the challenges that lie ahead so that you are not taken
by surprise. Do your research and make sure you are well prepared for critical
events, such as job interviews, applications, presentations and meetings.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/fool/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Magician">
			<number>I</number>
			<file>1.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Magician Tarot card typically appears in a Tarot reading at a time in your
life when you have the creative power and energy to create a new life cycle
for yourself. You have the ability to take the power of the Universe and
manifest your desires. The Magician Tarot card suggests that a situation has
been (or soon will be) presented to you that has all the inherent components
to allow the manifestation of your desires. Those desires may be spiritual
(fire), physical (earth), emotional (water), or mental (air), and are each
aligned with the four elements of the Tarot. You have the ability to make it
happen!  
  
With the Magician Tarot card, you are inspired to apply skill and initiative
to accomplish all your goals. You have a strong desire to begin something new,
to 'do, act, or go forth'. A 'can-do' attitude and strong sense of optimism
will dominate a new beginning and thus the decisions that you make will have
positive results.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Magician may represent your typical used-car salesman. He uses
his charm and his power in a manipulative manner to convince you of his point
of view. Always be careful of this type. Make sure you know what you are
buying into rather than being swept away by the excitement he generates.  
  
The Magician reversed often suggests that you may be out of touch with reality
and struggling to bring yourself back down to earth. There may be confusion,
impatience and lack of a clear plan. You need to return to the lesson of the
Fool and free yourself from the current situation in order to give yourself
some perspective and reassess the situation. Ask yourself, where am I focusing
my energy? Are my objectives clear? What skills and abilities are needed in
this situation? How am I communicating with others? What do I want others to
believe or see about me?

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/magician/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The High Priestess">
			<number>II</number>
			<file>2.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The High Priestess represents wisdom, serenity, knowledge and understanding.
She is often described as the guardian of the unconscious. She sits in front
of the thin veil of awareness, which is all that separates us from our inner
selves. The High Priestess knows the secret of how to access these realms. She
represents spiritual enlightenment and inner illumination, divine knowledge
and wisdom. She has a deep, intuitive understanding of the Universe and uses
this knowledge to teach rather than to try to control others. She generally
appears in a Tarot reading when you need to listen to and trust your inner
voice.  
  
The High Priestess Tarot card represents a link to the subconscious mind,
which cannot be accessed through the everyday world but only through dreams
and symbols. When this Tarot card appears in a Tarot reading, pay attention to
your dreams and intuition. Look for areas in your life that may be out of
balance or that require greater foresight and wisdom. Knowledge of how to fix
it will not come through logic or intellect but through your intuition so put
aside a time when you can meditate and listen to your own inner voice. Your
intuitive sense right now is providing you with useful and helpful information
and is assisting you to become more in touch with your subconscious mind.

</normal>
				<reversed>The High Priestess reversed can signify that you are not listening to your
inner voice and may need to take time for reflection and meditation. It is as
though your intuition is calling out to you but for some reason you have
switched off and are no longer really listening to what your subconscious is
trying to tell you. Think of the High Priestess as the calm centre inside of
you that is untouched by your external world and know that she is always there
when you need her. She is a part of you that you have not had much time to
connect with but she is an important part of you. Whenever you feel that
things are just getting too crazy and you are faced with impossible choices,
find a quiet space and listen to your inner voice. If you stop thinking about
your issues or just give yourself some space and time of 'nothingness', the
answer will come to you without having to even think about it. So, try
listening to the 'nothingness' and see what comes to you. There are some very
important answers that lie within that you can access right now.  
  
The reversed High Priestess also suggests in a Tarot reading that you are
normally an intuitive person who is connected with your inner self but in
recent times you have lost this connection. You may be rushing around and
worrying excessively about external issues and other people's problems that
you have lost focus on your own needs. You are not listening to your inner
guidance anymore and this is leading you further astray. The strong message
here is that you need to take some time out for YOU and you only, so that you
can tune into your inner voice and connect once again with your subconscious
mind. Meditation or spiritual study may help.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/highpriestess/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Empress">
			<number>III</number>
			<file>3.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Empress shows a deep connection with our femininity. Femininity translates
in many ways - beauty, sensuality, fertility, creative expression, nurturing -
and is necessary in creating balance in both men and women. The Empress calls
on you to connect with your feminine energy. Create beauty in your life. Get
in touch with your sensuality through taste, touch, sound, smell and sight.
Draw on these senses to experience pleasure and deep fulfilment. Treat
yourself to a day spa, learn massage, enjoy a fine dining experience, or
simply spend more time with your partner. Discover new ways to creatively
express yourself, be it through painting, music, drama, or other art forms.
This may be the perfect time to take up a new hobby that enables you to access
this part of yourself.  
  
The Empress may also indicate pregnancy or birth. Look to other cards in the
reading to confirm if this is an actual pregnancy or birth (for example, the
Ace or Page of Cups or the Four of Wands) or if it is metaphorical (for
example, the Ace of Wands). On a metaphorical level, the Empress may represent
the birth of a new idea, a product, or a new way of being. New ideas and
projects will be implemented resulting in the success of all your projects and
interests. Bring forth those ideas that have been growing and developing
inside of you.

</normal>
				<reversed>Reversed, the Empress suggests a loss of personal power through placing too
much emphasis on another person's emotional or material needs, thus neglecting
your own. The reversed position of this card deals with indecisiveness
concerning others and confusion about the direction a relationship may be
taking. You may also be finding it difficult to work cooperatively with
others. The reason for this lack of harmony is likely to be within you and
therefore introspection is required.  
  
More generally, the Empress reversed indicates that you are feeling
discontented because something is missing or lacking in your life, or because
you want to find something creative, meaningful or fulfilling to do but you do
not know what. This card can indicate a creative block. You may find your mood
is depressed or negative. Work can feel laborious and mundane. This is not a
time to think, act or do. You are already overloaded and mental pursuits will
not give you what you need. Further attempts to follow your intellect or
reasoning mind will only cause frustration or lead you astray.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/empress/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Emperor">
			<number>IV</number>
			<file>4.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Emperor is the father figure of the Tarot deck. He is the 'provider' and
protects and defends his loved ones. He has established a solid family line
and is often seen as the patriarch of a wide network of family members. He
offers guidance, advice and wisdom to others and in doing so, demonstrates
authority and grounding. His wisdom is obtained through worldly, life
experience. He has 'been there, done that', and has the battle armour to prove
it. He takes what he has learned, and passes it on to the next generation, so
someday they can be as wise and powerful as he is. He brings security and
comfort to those around him.  
  
The Emperor is also representative of structure and stability. He is able to
create order out of chaos by carefully categorising his thoughts and mapping
out what needs to be done to solve the problem. He is a systematic and
strategic thinker and is highly organised and coordinated in his approach. He
sticks to a plan and ensures he sees it out until the end. Thus, this card
indicates that you have a strong desire to see your ideas manifested on the
physical plane in the form of material gain or accomplishment. An opportunity
will arrive that could be the foundation of a very successful future.

</normal>
				<reversed>You may feel powerless when the Emperor reversed appears in a reading. Dealing
with authority is fraught with difficulties at this time and whether this
manifests as a dominant partner, problems with your father or battles with
officials, you do not seem to be making any headway. Paradoxically, freedom
lies within such structures now. This is not the time to rebel, instead try to
get in touch with your own need to control events and deal with any problems
logically.  
  
Sometimes, the reversed Emperor asks you to stand up to authority and to know
that you do not always have to go about matters in the most traditional way.
You may be fed up with an over-bearing boss or a hierarchical organisation and
you will be compelled to enter a more flexible and adaptive environment. You
may also be inspired to work independently, perhaps even starting up your own
business in order to be free of corporate life and oppressive bosses!

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/emperor/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Hierophant">
			<number>V</number>
			<file>5.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Hierophant is very conventional and this Tarot card suggests that you have
a desire to follow due process and to stay within the conventional bounds of
what is typically an orthodox approach. Instead of being innovative, you will
need to adapt to the existing set of beliefs and systems that are already in
place. You will need to do what is expected of you. The appearance of the
Hierophant in a Tarot reading indicates that this is certainly not a time to
challenge the status quo!  
  
The Hierophant Tarot card suggests that you may be wise to follow established
social structures and traditions. You may be involved in some sort of ritual,
ceremony, or the trappings of religion. There is also a need to honour some
tradition in your life, or maybe start some traditions of your own if you have
none. Consider also exploring your spiritual or religious heritage.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Hierophant reversed indicates that you are feeling restricted or
constrained by structure and rules, and as a result, you have lost a lot of
flexibility and control in your life. You have a strong desire to go against
the grain and break free from convention. You may be tempted to go about your
business in an unorthodox manner, to do something that is out of character or
against social norms. The Hierophant reversed is about breaking the rules and
challenging the status quo. You no longer accept the rigid structures,
tradition and dogma surrounding you, and now seek out opportunities to rebel
and retaliate. You want to challenge ideas and concepts that you once thought
of as written in stone.  
  
The reversed Hierophant is about questioning tradition and asking yourself
whether what you are doing is really the right thing by you. You may have been
running on automatic so far and following the crowd but now you realise that
perhaps things are not the way they seem and changes need to be made.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/hierophant/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Lovers">
			<number>VI</number>
			<file>6.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Lovers can also indicate a very strong sexual connection that goes beyond
instant gratification and lust to suggest a very deep desire and passion that
exists between two beings. The physical attraction is strong and so too is the
desire to be intimate with one another.  
  
On a more personal level, the Lovers card represents the establishment of a
personal belief system and becoming clearer about your own values. This is a
time when you are figuring out what you stand for and what your personal
philosophy on life is. Having gone through the indoctrination of the
Hierophant, you are now ready to establish your own belief system and make up
your own mind about what is and what is not important in life. This is also a
time when you need to stay true to yourself and be as authentic and genuine as
possible.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Lovers reversed indicates that you are avoiding responsibility for the
consequences of your own actions. You have made a rushed decision based purely
on your desire for instant gratification and now you are trying to lay the
blame on others or on fate. You must do what you can to make amends but if
this is not possible, let the past go and resolve to make better choices in
the future.  
  
The Lovers reversed can also indicate inner conflicts and being at war with
yourself rather than with external forces. It suggests disharmony and
difficulty in being able to balance your own inner union. Perhaps you are
punishing yourself for something you have done or feel responsible for? To
help you out of this situation, you will need to focus on clearly articulating
your personal belief systems and values. This will help to guide you in making
better decisions next time. In addition, you may need to return to the energy
of the Hierophant and seek the counsel and advice of an institution or
spiritual mentor.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/lovers/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Chariot">
			<number>VII</number>
			<file>7.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Chariot represents conquest, victory and overcoming opposition through
your confidence and control. Any success will be a result of applying these
factors to the situation. You will need to use the strength of your willpower
to overcome any obstacles or challenges in your way. You may even find that by
leveraging any opposing forces surrounding you at this time you can use them
to your advantage. You must be determined, self-disciplined, and hard working.
If you are, you will triumph over any difficulties or anyone who is trying to
limit you. This struggle will ultimately make you stronger.  
  
You will be successful at pursuing your goals, so long as you maintain focus,
determination and confidence in your abilities. You need to focus completely
on the task at hand, get in the race and win it. You have to dominate and beat
the competition. You must cultivate the ability to withstand the rigours of
what is required. In fact, striving towards your goal can be as satisfying as
attaining it. This is a time to be strong and in control. You must also draw
upon your willpower and self-discipline.

</normal>
				<reversed>Reversed, the Chariot suggests that you are feeling as if you have very little
control over your life. You may have lost steering power over the opposing
forces and you are now at their mercy. You may feel dragged through time, in
whatever direction fate takes you. If you are someone who likes to have some
control over your destiny and to know where you are heading, this is the time
to tighten the reins and become more disciplined and focused on what you are
doing. While the feeling of loss of power can be quite demoralising, the key
is to look at what you can control and what you cannot control. Do not allow
yourself to be worried about what is out of your control as there is nothing
you can do about it. Instead, focus your energies on what IS in your control.
Examine what you can do to change the situation. At this stage, you need to be
able to feel as if you have at least some direction, because currently you
feel pushed and pulled around in the sea of fate.  
  
The Chariot reversed also suggests that you are collapsing under pressure and
losing your self-control. Your aggression is being channelled in the wrong
direction, wildly at other people, at fate, at external circumstances. This is
a complete waste of your energy and resources. Redefine your aggression as
determination and willpower, stop clinging weakly to unrewarding ideas,
habits, people, and objects and move forward.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/chariot/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Strength">
			<number>VIII</number>
			<file>8.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Strength Tarot card represents strength, determination, and power in a
manner similar to the Chariot. However, the differences between the two Tarot
cards are obvious. Where the Chariot represents outer strength and will, the
Strength card represents inner strength and the power of the human spirit to
overcome any obstacle. The meaning of the Strength Tarot card is about knowing
that you can endure life's obstacles by drawing upon your inner strength and
confidence. You have great stamina and persistence, tempered by an underlying
patience and inner calm. You are focused on what you need to do, and you go
about it in a way that demonstrates great composure and maturity.  
  
The Strength Tarot card also reflects a compassionate approach. You are like
the woman in this card who offers love and patience to the ferocious lion in
order to be able to tame him. You give others space and you are tolerant of
their needs. You are accepting and can easily forgive any imperfections. In
doing this, you create a safe and trusting environment where you can then
gently influence others. This demonstrates a level of 'soft' control,
persuading and coaxing others to your way of thinking.

</normal>
				<reversed>Strength reversed indicates weakness. You may have recently experienced a
setback, or you are questioning your own journey and whether you are on the
right track. Your inner strength and courage is lacking right now and you are
feeling inadequate and vulnerable as a result. While these feelings may seem
very real when you are in the moment, you will soon come to realise that they
exist only to remind you that you are only temporarily out of touch with your
inner strength. You need to remember that your core strength will always be
with you and now is as good a time as any to reconnect with this core
strength. Look towards the positive aspects in your life to reinvigorate self-
confidence and self-esteem. Return to the lesson of the Chariot, where you
need to draw upon your willpower, focus and determination in order to overcome
your obstacles and be victorious.  
  
Similarly, the reversed Strength Tarot card suggests that you may be starting
to doubt yourself and lose some self-esteem and self-confidence. Instead of
taking the lead and manifesting your goals, you may be engaging in self-doubt
and becoming dependent on others' feelings and actions that then dictate your
own.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/strength/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Hermit">
			<number>XI</number>
			<file>9.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Hermit Tarot card suggests that you are in a phase of introspection where
you are drawing your attention and focus inward and looking for answers
within. You have a strong need to understand, not just at the surface level
but to really know why life is the way it is. The Hermit reflects that your
consciousness has moved inward and you now realise that the truth and
understanding you seek is within yourself and not in the distractions of the
outside world. This is a perfect time to take a step back from your day-to-day
life and deeply contemplate your motivations, personal principles and values.  
  
The Hermit reflects that you are engaging in a period of soul searching. You
want to seek the truth at all costs. You desire a new direction in life and,
as a result, have recently begun a journey of self-discovery and
contemplation. There comes a point in life when we begin to question the
status quo, knowing that there is a deeper meaning to life, and thus, we begin
to search for it. This search is mainly a solitary quest because the answers
do not lie in the external world but within us. Thus, the Hermit Tarot card
indicates a time when you seek solitude and isolation from others. You need to
be alone and you want to withdraw from the world around you. This is so that
you can retreat further into your own private world and experience a deep
sense of seclusion.

</normal>
				<reversed>The reversed Hermit can go one of two ways. You are either not taking enough
time for personal reflection, or you are taking too much. If you are
struggling to connect more deeply with your spiritual self, the Hermit
reversed encourages you to create more time and space so that you can meditate
and reflect on your spiritual self. It is time to go more deeply into your
inner being and rediscover your greater meaning and purpose on this earth. You
may have been so busy dealing with the day-to-day issues that you have
forgotten to reflect inwardly and listen to your inner voice. The Hermit asks
you to search deep within your soul to help you find your way again and to
focus on rebuilding yourself on a spiritual level.  
  
If you have already been spending a lot of time reflecting on your inner self,
then the appearance of the reversed Hermit may suggest that you are spending
too much time alone in excessive isolation. You are literally becoming a
hermit and cutting yourself off from others. While this period is helping you
on a spiritual level, you may be feeling temporarily isolated and alone. Do
not underestimate the value of staying connected with others, even while you
are going through your own spiritual journey. Be mindful, too, of other
people's needs. You do not want to become so absorbed in yourself and your
personal dilemmas that you shut out your family and friends.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/hermit/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Wheel of Fortune">
			<number>X</number>
			<file>10.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Wheel of Fortune refers to the fact that things tend to go in cycles.
There are good times and there are bad times. Even if your external
environment is difficult and challenging, there will come a time when this
will ease off and you will be able to focus more on creating fun and
frivolity. The lesson of the Wheel of Fortune is that you must accept that
there are always ups and downs in life. If you were to have only good times,
you would become less appreciative of what you have. Sometimes the bad times
provide the contrast and perspective you need to be able to recognise how
blessed you are when the good times come. So, when times are good, enjoy the
benefits but do not become complacent because things can change. When times
are bad, do not be discouraged because even when things seem their worst it
simply suggests that things can only get better!  
  
The Wheel of Fortune suggests that you should not simply stand still and
accept what life hands you. You can take an active hand to try and remain on
the upside of the Wheel. When things are down, instead of waiting and hoping
for things to get better, you can work actively towards improving your
situation, thereby speeding up the recovery process. Finally, the Wheel asks
you to not become discouraged when faced with adversity. Adversity is a
natural part of life and should be expected from time to time. The fact that
bad times happen should not worry you. Accept them as natural and not
necessarily indicative of problems. Instead, look for ways in which you can
face and conquer the adversity. If it cannot be addressed, then that might be
taken as a suggestion of a problem.

</normal>
				<reversed>When the Wheel of Fortune is reversed, luck is not on your side. There has
been a turn of events that are not in your favour sending you into a tail spin
and changing your world significantly, seemingly for the worst. Oftentimes,
the reversed Wheel of Fortune indicates that there are negative forces at play
that are outside of your control, leaving you feeling helpless and powerless.
However, while there have been some unfortunate circumstances that are outside
of your control, the run of bad luck that you are experiencing may also be as
a result of poor decisions you have made in the past. Think about what actions
you have taken recently and whether these may have contributed to your present
circumstances. What can you do to improve your luck and regain control of your
destiny? Despite the setbacks, learn from the cycle of life and be prepared
for such ups and downs in the future. Accept responsibility for your current
and future situation, and look for ways that you can create more positive
outcomes.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/wheel-of-fortune/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Justice">
			<number>XI</number>
			<file>11.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>Put simply, the Justice card represents justice, fairness, truth and the law.
As an outcome, the Justice card indicates that the fairest decision will be
made. You are being called to account for your actions and be judged
accordingly. Notice that Justice's scales are balanced, thus its appearance
indicates that events have worked out as they were meant to work out and that
what is happening to you comes from the decisions you have made and the
actions you have taken in the past. You have what you deserve.  
  
Justice represents a conscious awareness that your decisions and actions have
long-term consequences and your present and future circumstances are most
likely a result of these decisions and actions. At the same time, Justice
shows that your actions in the future can be changed by a lesson learned in
the present situation. You cannot become honest without extending that honesty
to yourself and others.

</normal>
				<reversed>Reversed, Justice indicates dishonesty to yourself and others. It shows an
unwillingness to understand the deeper meaning of why an event has occurred
and shows that you are missing some opportunity for a greater understanding of
yourself in life. You are not actively accepting responsibility for your
actions and may be trying to 'dodge the bullet' and blame others for your
mistakes. The key here is to take responsibility for your own situation and
realise that you are here through your own past choices, and therefore,
whatever it takes to get out of the situation is fair and just according to
Universal principles of karma and justice.  
  
If, after a very hard look at yourself, you feel that you have done the best
job possible, know that the Universe has a path laid out for you and while
your situation may be frustrating right now, it is the right path for you.
Over time you will begin to see that it does indeed have a reason for being
this way.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/justice/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Hanged Man">
			<number>XII</number>
			<file>12.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Hanged Man reflects a need to suspend action, and as a result, a period of
indecision may be indicated. Decisions or actions that need to be implemented
will be postponed, even if, at the time, there is a sense of urgency to act.
In fact, you may be much better off if you can stall on any decision-making
and action-taking at this time in order to provide yourself with more time to
reflect on the situation at hand and to consider the greater good. If you can
buy yourself some more time or hold off on any further activities for a short
period, then you may actually create a different, and better, outcome. This is
a card that is all about suspension and waiting, and suggests that this may be
just what you need to do in order to allow new possibilities to arise.
Sometimes not acting will help to shed more light on what other options are
available to you and will allow more attractive opportunities to emerge.  
  
The Hanged Man can sometimes reflect that you are feeling stuck or restricted
in your life. You need to get in touch with why you are feeling this way, and
work to release yourself from these restrictions. In this way, the Hanged Man
is also about letting go. You need an emotional release from whatever it is
that is leaving you feeling stuck. Accept and surrender to your present
circumstances. You may need to become more vulnerable and open to different
experiences but this will help you end the struggle and give up your need for
control. It is when you can really let go of all the worries and concerns that
you have, that you find these concerns suddenly disappear and a new reality is
possible.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Hanged Man reversed represents a period when you feel you are sacrificing
a lot and getting nothing in return. You may have felt things were at an
absolute standstill, with no movement or resolution. It is as though you are
suspended in time and unable to make a move forward, backward or even sideways
to get out of your current situation. Your own goals and dreams are put on
hold because of external realities or internal issues. This is an energy that
is passing out of your life and you can now expect things to start happening
once again and major changes to occur. This period of suspension is like a
catalyst for what is to come.  
  
You may be putting off making a decision, in the hope that it will all sort
itself out eventually. However, this is often just wishful thinking. What is
happening is that you are simply stalling the inevitable and you will at some
point be pushed to make a final decision and to make a sacrifice in the
process. In a reading where a relationship has been put on hold, the Hanged
Man reversed suggests that you are happy to wait around, to a point. You
realise that this relationship will evolve over time and that, due to its
complexities, it cannot be rushed. However, you also do not want to be 'on
hold' forever and you acknowledge that there will come a time when you must
make a decision about your current relationship.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/hangedman/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Death">
			<number>XIII</number>
			<file>13.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Death card is probably the most feared and misunderstood of all the cards
in the Tarot deck. Just the mention of the card's name has people shaking in
their boots! In general, people tend to take the meaning of this card far too
literally and fear that the indication is for the death of either themselves
or others. Relax! The card of Death can be one of the most fruitful and
positive cards in the deck.  
  
Death is symbolic of the ending of a major phase or aspect of your life that
may bring about the beginning of something far more valuable and important.
You must close one door in order to open another. You need to put the past
behind you and part ways, ready to embrace new opportunities and
possibilities. It may be difficult to let go of the past at times but you will
soon see how important it is so that you can bring renewal and transformation
into your life. If you resist these necessary endings, you may experience
pain, both emotionally and physically but if you exercise your creative
imagination and visualise a new possibility, you allow more constructive
patterns to emerge.

</normal>
				<reversed>Death is a card of transformation and new life, and typically shows a need to
start completely over by letting go of the past. Death reversed typically
reflects that you are on the verge of major change but for some reason, you
are resisting making that change. You may be reluctant to let go of the past
or you may not know how to make the change you need. You are still carrying
harmful aspects from the past that may interfere with the opportunity you have
for a new beginning. You are refusing to accept change and you are resisting
any element of change that may arise in your life. As a result, life has
stagnated and you are feeling 'stuck' in limbo.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/death/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Temperance">
			<number>XIV</number>
			<file>14.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>Temperance indicates that you are learning to bring about balance, patience
and moderation in your life. You have been able to take the middle road,
avoiding extremes and maintaining a great sense of calm in your life. You have
learned to keep calm in situations of great stress or anxiety, and you give
the impression of being a swan, paddling madly underneath the water but
appearing so graceful and elegant on the surface. You do not let things get to
you, and you have found a place of peace where you can put things into
perspective when things get hectic. Your respect for balance and tranquillity
is what will help you to achieve and experience fulfilment in your life. Your
temperament will be well balanced and you demonstrate good management and
balance in your outlook on life. The Temperance card reflects that you have a
clear, long-term vision of what you want to achieve. You are not rushing
things along; rather you are taking your time to ensure that you do the best
job you can. This card also reflects a higher learning in what you are doing
and demonstrates that you are learning a great deal on your journey. You are
at peace with what you are doing and it is all coming together very well. Your
inner voice is guiding you gently to the right outcome and you are patiently
listening and following. You have a very balanced perspective on the situation
at this time and you are in a very good position to make the right choices.

</normal>
				<reversed>Temperance reversed reflects a time when something is out of balance, in
conflict or excessive, and is therefore creating stress and tension in your
life. Look to the other cards in the reading to understand what is out of
balance or contributing to this feeling. Temperance reversed can also be a
lead indicator that, were you to follow a certain path, you would create
imbalance in the situation. You may be acting impatiently or refusing to take
the moderate, gentle approach. Be wary of hasty action as this will only lead
to further imbalance.  
  
Temperance reversed can suggest that you lack a long-term vision and/or
purpose and, as a result, you are feeling out of balance. This is a time when
you need to reflect on what changes are necessary in your life to create
greater purpose and fulfilment. Return to the energy of the Death card to
understand what you need to leave behind you in the past and what changes you
need to embrace in the future.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/temperance/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Devil">
			<number>XV</number>
			<file>15.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>When you see the Devil in a reading, ask yourself where you are feeling stuck
or restricted in your life. You may be tricked into believing that you are
being controlled by external forces when in fact you have created your own
chains of imprisonment and powerlessness. A sense of hopelessness can
accompany the Devil. You feel despair and have a pessimistic view of life
because you feel that so much is outside of your control. You fear the worst,
and this means that your fears have a hold over you and prevent you from
leading a more fulfilling and optimistic life. What are the addictions or
attachments restraining you from experiencing the freedom of the Fool? Are you
giving yourself over to the illusion of helplessness and despair? Know that
you have the power within to free yourself from the bondage of the Devil.  
  
The Devil often reflects actual addictions and dependencies in your life, such
as alcoholism, drug-taking, unhealthy relationships, over-spending and the
like. You think you need something and you are willing to go against what you
know to be right and true in order to obtain it. You need to break free of
these negative patterns of behaviour by acknowledging the hold that they have
over you and the negative impact they are having on your life. Often they are
behaviours that are immediately gratifying but which cause longer-term damage
to your inner fulfilment.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Devil appears when you are feeling trapped by things such as unhealthy or
co-dependent relationships, financial debt, unproductive careers, unhealthy
lifestyles or addictions, or consumerism and materialism. When the Devil is
reversed, it indicates a growing awareness that you are currently in this
state and you desire freedom from these harmful bonds. You may now be more
willing and able to accept changes in your life and you may be more open to
taking on new perspectives. However, it is not going to be an easy journey.
You will need to battle your inner fears and anxieties to free yourself from
the chains that bind you to your unhealthy habits. You need to conduct an
audit of your life and eliminate those things that you know are harmful to you
and your inner psyche. It may be about creating a healthier diet, watching
less television, quitting smoking, spending more time with your loved ones, or
focusing more clearly on your goals. Take this opportunity to bring about
positive change in your life by providing yourself with ongoing encouragement
and motivation. You must remain faithful to your goal of freedom.  
  
If you have not yet succumbed to bad habits or addictions, be cautious about
opening yourself up to these temptations in the future. Look out for anything
that might put you in debt or under the control of another person who may not
have the best of intentions. Avoid anything that might harm your body
physically, such as alcohol, drugs, or any other addictions because these will
prove to be very difficult to shake off later. You may believe they are only a
temporary and harmless release from your personal issues but they may turn
into a significant problem that could cause you a lot of grief in the long-
term.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/devil/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Tower">
			<number>XVI</number>
			<file>16.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>When you see the Tower in a reading, you may feel afraid, shaken and insecure.
It is a time of great turmoil and destruction as you seek to understand how
you could have been so wrong, so naive, or so blind about a particularly
situation. And now, what will you do and how will you manage in the face of
this shocking truth? You may be experiencing sleepless nights, depression,
grief, anger and confrontation. These are normal reactions to major changes in
your outer and inner worlds.  
  
A Tower experience is any experience that shakes the foundation of your
current sense of security and/or forces you to question your strongly-held
beliefs, perceptions, attitudes and behaviours. It may be a divorce, death of
a loved one, financial failure, health problems or job loss, or any event that
penetrates to the core of your inner being, affecting you spiritually,
mentally and physically. It is often descriptive of a major upheaval,
disruption, emergency or crisis, and is likely to bring chaos in the aftermath
of such an event.

</normal>
				<reversed>Upright, the Tower indicates a time of great turmoil and destruction, which
will eventually bring with it change and regeneration. Reversed, however, the
Tower card indicates that you are simply delaying the necessary 'destruction'.
You need to go through this difficult time in order to learn an important
lesson. Do not resist it. Even though it is shocking and hard to deal with, it
is a very important part of your life journey.  
  
Similarly, the Tower reversed suggests that, while you consciously want change
and transformation, you seem to be afraid of these two things. You may feel
that change and transformation may bring with it destruction and pain, and
thus you are resisting this. You may be aware that in order to create the BIG
change you are seeking, you need to go through a period of significant
discomfort but you seem to be afraid of this discomfort. Now is the time to
think BIG and to not be afraid of taking BIG leaps ahead of you. Sure, the
stakes are high and it is risky territory but if you really want to achieve
the scale of change you aspire to, then you need to take some risk.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/tower/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Star">
			<number>XVII</number>
			<file>17.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Star Tarot card brings renewed hope and faith and a sense that you are
truly blessed by the Universe at this time. Courage, fulfilment, and
inspiration are in your life. You are entering a loving phase in your life,
filled with calm energy, mental stability and deeper understanding of both
yourself and others around you. This card is saying to you that, over the
long-term, you should have faith and trust in the Universe. A better future is
waiting for you but in order to reach it you must trust that it is indeed
possible.  
  
As it follows the Tower, the meaning of the Star Tarot card suggests that you
have endured life's challenges and have been through a difficult time but you
are now open to healing and transformation. Your ability to let go of damaging
memories has been strengthened by contact with your true self through these
difficult times. Hatred, envy, bitterness, and revenge have burned themselves
out and no longer shadow your life or get in the way of your potential for
future happiness. You are now also able to forgive and forget so that you can
embrace new opportunities.

</normal>
				<reversed>When the Star is reversed, it suggests that your spiritual mission is
distorted. Instead of hope, you are feeling despair or discouragement. Instead
of being filled with positive possibilities, you find yourself dwelling on
negative issues. Negative thoughts will wear away at you to the point where
you may give up control of the situation and concede defeat. To remedy this,
the reversed Star suggests you identify what is making you feel discouraged or
overwhelmed and work on moving past these issues. They can take on an
importance far greater than they deserve and can hold you back.  
  
In a Tarot reading, the reversed Star card also indicates that you are
beginning to feel disengaged and uninspired with life or components of your
life (for example, work, hobbies, relationships, personal projects, etc.).
Perhaps you started out with great vision and enthusiasm but you are now
finding yourself overwhelmed by day-to-day routines that are boring and
dreary. You may find life a chore now, when it used to be such a pleasant
experience. This Tarot card is particularly relevant for career readings, when
you are feeling that you are no longer connected to the work you do and you
feel that you need to move on or make a significant change to your career.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/star/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Moon">
			<number>XVIII</number>
			<file>18.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Moon is a card of illusion and deception, and therefore often suggests a
time when something is not as it appears to be. Vigilance and clear perception
will be necessary to find that which is hidden before it is too late. If other
cards in the reading are positive, then the Moon shows that not all is as
wonderful as you would think and there are still hidden forces at play that
may unravel your success. You may be idealising the situation, and ignoring
the fact that potential for failure exists among success. If the other cards
are generally negative, then the Moon suggests that you are letting your
imagination run away with you, and that things are not nearly as bad as they
seem. In both cases you must open your eyes and see what it really going on.
Guard against accepting illusions as they may cause an error in your
judgement.  
  
Oftentimes, the Moon appears in a reading when you are not sure of your
destination, or even of the path you are travelling but you travel
nonetheless. You may have lost your way and are now left to walk in the dark,
guided only by your inner light and intuition. You need to go on without a
clear picture of where you are, where you are going or where you have been.
The Moon is a card of intuition and psychic forces, so let go of your
conscious mental blocks or negative self-talk, and allow your intuition to
guide you. Your dreams, intuitions, and inner promptings lead you forward
toward higher levels of understanding if you listen carefully and use your
judgement to help interpret the veiled messages of the unconscious. Not only
will the way forward be revealed but in many cases you will learn lessons
about yourself that will be valuable in later journeys.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Moon reversed indicates that you have recently experienced a time of self-
deception, illusion, fears and anxiety but these negative energies are
beginning to subside. You may have also been dealing with some deeper
emotional issues that have previously been sitting beneath the surface. While
this has created some discomfort and turmoil as you deal with these deeper
issues, you are starting to feel as if a weight has been lifted and that you
can be less fearful and anxious about your life situation. You are beginning
to work through your inner fears and anxieties, understanding the impact that
these have on your life and how you can eventually free yourself from these
limiting beliefs. This can be a wonderfully liberating and transformational
experience.  
  
A reversed Moon may indicate a fundamental unhappiness with your present
situation but also confusion over what else you could do and what you really
want to do. It may be that you believe that what you really want to do with
your life is impractical or unrealistic, or your past experiences in life have
convinced you that you are stuck with what you have and it is too late to
change now. These emotional issues are preventing you from moving forward. To
overcome this, it is essential to confront your innermost fears and
assumptions to gain self-confidence and direction. You need to believe in
yourself and know that it is possible to create balance in your life. You may
also find that your dreams provide you with important clues as to what
direction you need to take. Pay attention to the subtle, subconscious messages
that come to you in this way.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/moon/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The Sun">
			<number>XIX</number>
			<file>19.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Sun represents success, radiance and abundance. The Sun gives you strength
and tells you that no matter where you go or what you do, your positive and
radiant energy will follow you and will bring you happiness and joy. People
are drawn to you because you can always see the bright side and you bring such
warmth into other people's lives. This beautiful, warm energy is what will get
you through the tough times and will help you succeed. You are also in a
position where you can share your highest qualities and achievements with
others. Radiate who you are and what you stand for. Shine love on those you
care about.  
  
You have an innate sense of confidence right now. Life is good, the sun is
shining and you are on your way to achieving your goals. The Sun represents
that feeling of getting up on Saturday morning, with the whole weekend ahead
of you, and you open the curtains with the sun shining on your face. Having
struggled through the shadow sides you now know yourself and know where you
are heading, and the sun illuminates your path.

</normal>
				<reversed>The Sun reversed indicates that finding the positive aspects to a particular
situation may prove to be difficult. The clouds may be blocking out the
warmth, and preventing you from feeling as though everything is on track. You
may have experienced setbacks that have damaged your enthusiasm and optimism
and have perhaps led you to question whether you can really achieve what you
have set out to achieve. You may be feeling depressed, sad or left out. You
may be reluctant to proceed and you are no longer enjoying what you are doing.
Your direction and path ahead may have become clouded or distorted in some
way. Nonetheless, the Sun is never a negative card, so this is only temporary.
The obstacles you see can be easily removed if you put your mind to it. It may
just take a little more effort than usual.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/sun/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="Judgement">
			<number>XX</number>
			<file>20.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The Judgement card suggests that you have had a recent epiphany or an
'awakening' where you have come to a realisation that you need to live your
life in a different way and you need to be true to yourself and your needs.
You have opened yourself up to a new possibility - to lead a fulfilling life
that serves your higher needs and that offers inspiration and hope to others.
You feel as though you have had a 'calling' in life, and you are getting much
closer to the point where you need to take action. Something that was lying
dormant within you, some unconscious knowledge or truth is finally being
awakened and brought into the light. With its theme of awakening to new life,
the Judgement card suggests that you have reviewed and evaluated your past
experiences and have learned from them. All the pieces of the puzzle of your
life are finally coming together to form one, integrated picture of your life
story. This integration has healed any deep wounds and you are now in a
position to put the past behind you. Your memories no longer haunt you, and
you are able to understand and value what has happened to you and what it has
taught you about life. Now, you are ready to confront any unfinished business
in your life, clear up any misunderstandings and view the future with peace
and deep 'knowingness' in your heart.

</normal>
				<reversed>Reversed, the Judgement card suggests that you may be indulging yourself in
doubt and self-judgement. Your deliberation is causing you to miss the new
opportunities that await. A certain amount of momentum has accumulated behind
what you have achieved, which could propel you further. If actions are taken
now, such momentum will not be lost. Therefore now is not the time for being
cautious or introverted, rather it is time to move onwards with confidence and
pride.  
  
On the other hand, the Judgement card asks you to take a moment out of your
usual routine and busy lifestyle to stop and think about your life so far and
what you can learn from your life. In its reversed position, it may indicate
that you are not allowing yourself sufficient time and space to really get to
the heart of the matter and draw from your lessons of the past. Additionally,
this card suggests that you may be overly hard or critical of yourself and not
allowing yourself to truly learn from your mistakes. You may have made some
mistakes in the past but see these as learning experiences rather than
failures or faults.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/judgement/</source>
		</card>
		<card name="The World">
			<number>XXI</number>
			<file>21.png</file>
			<meaning>
				<normal>The World signifies completion, achievement and fulfilment. All of your
efforts are finally paying off and you have reached the end of a journey or
have completed a major life cycle. You have endured hardships and challenges
along the way but these have only made you stronger and significantly wiser
and more experienced than when you first started on your journey.  
  
A long-term project, period of study, relationship, or career has come full
circle and you are now feeling a sense of closure as well as achievement and
accomplishment. It could represent a graduation, a marriage, the birth of a
child (representing the end of a pregnancy), or the attainment of a long held
dream or aspiration. You have finally accomplished your goal or purpose.
Everything has come together, and you are in the right place, doing the right
thing, achieving what you have envisioned, and feeling fulfilled and complete.
In this sense, the World card also heralds new beginnings that naturally
emerge out of the completion cycle.

</normal>
				<reversed>Upright, the World represents completion. When reversed, however, the World
suggests that you are trying to achieve completion in your life but you may
not be taking all the steps necessary to achieve your goals. There is a
tendency to take the easiest or quickest path to attain your goal but often
this does not lead to the outcome you had originally intended. Instead,
through facing up to the challenges along the way, you will learn and grow
exponentially and will feel such an amazing sense of achievement when you
finally make it to your goal. So, do not be afraid to set yourself 'stretch'
goals, even if it means enduring hardships or challenges along the way. This
will make victory even sweeter.  
  
The reversed World can also indicate a time when you are close to reaching
completion but for whatever reason, you lose focus and slack off right at the
end. You only have a short way to go, so why lose focus now? Re-energise
yourself and remind yourself how wonderful life will be when you have finally
reached your goal.

</reversed>
			</meaning>
			<source>http://www.biddytarot.com/tarot-card-meanings/major-arcana/world/</source>
		</card>
	</suit>
</deck>
